<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Harper Reed: Tech, Mobile, Yo-yoing and Death Metal</title>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://localhost:4000"/>
 <updated>2010-07-04T13:09:49-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://localhost:4000</id>

 
 <author>
   <name>Harper Reed</name>
   <email>harper@nata2.org</email>
 </author>
 
 
 
 <entry>
   <title>Smitten by the iPad: thoughts and complaints. </title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2010/04/05/smitten-by-the-ipad-thoughts-and-complaints.html"/>
   <updated>2010-04-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2010/04/05/smitten-by-the-ipad-thoughts-and-complaints</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;The ipad is awesome by nata2, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/natatwo/4488064118/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4052/4488064118_ea9d770433_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The ipad is awesome&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I was tricked by the gravitational forces that an apple product announcement causes into visiting the apple store. Five hundred bucks later I walked out of the apple store with a fancy new iPad. Excited and Doh!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iPad is a new and very exciting paradigm for computing. I played with it afternoon and it felt very minority report. It felt like the future. no physical keyboard. I was controlling things with my finger/mind. it was awesome. I am smitten.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides the irrational distortion field emitted by this shiny device, I have some general thoughts/complaints on the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The lack of camera is irrational.&lt;/strong&gt; I have no idea why apple didn't include two cameras on the iPad. It would be an amazing device for parents, students, people, etc. Chatting is annoying on non-multitasking devices, however it might be nice to Skype with a slate like device. It will obviously be added to the next iteration of this device.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The iWork cloud platform is annoying.&lt;/strong&gt; Importing and exporting documents is very hard. It is obviously not meant to be used by people who have documents already. The only way to get shit on the device is to download it. Why wouldn't Apple integrate iWork with MobileMe? silly. Google will have to change their Docs platform to allow easy downloading from the mobile google docs page.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The lack of any clock or alarm app very strange.&lt;/strong&gt; I use the clock app on the iphone for a lot of stuff. not having that is a bummer. but in the grand scheme of bummers its about a 0.00001/5.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no usb host mode&lt;/strong&gt; (that i know of). I would love to charge my phone, etc via USB with this device. it would minimize the number of cables and what not i would bring. It would also be awesome to plugin external disks or keyboards to it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Reader blows on the iPad.&lt;/strong&gt; This is a real bummer since that is pretty much the one thing i want to have all the time. You can't scroll with the desktop version and the mobile version seems silly on the iPad. I can't wait for Google to &quot;fix&quot; all of their webapps for the iPad.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Using an iPhone after spending a lot of time on the iPad makes the iPhone seem like a midget&lt;/strong&gt;. It makes the nexus one seems like it is made out of paper.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The iPad is probably one of the coolest ways to show presentations to someone while sitting at a bar.&lt;/strong&gt; I have been pitching some ideas to people and having the iPad with my deck is pretty awesome. A great way to go over your presentation with one or two people. Way better than a laptop.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Kindle app is awesome&lt;/strong&gt;. I like it a lot. I want to try reading a book on the iPad, but i really like the kindle's screen.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most of the apps are boring.&lt;/strong&gt; Seriously. The apps that are impressive are: Kayak, Maps, Photos, Kindle, Twitterrific, instapaper, Netflix and Square&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://squareup.com/&quot;&gt;Square&lt;/a&gt; is one of the coolest apps I have seen.&lt;/strong&gt; It should blow peoples minds. I imagine that it will be a game changer for friends who do retail. I can't wait for my square card reader to show up. I will be charging my friends for everything.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is an amazing device for casual internet use.&lt;/strong&gt; I imagine that Hiromi, my parents, my brother and anyone else who isn't attached to a computer all day long would love these devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Overall the iPad is amazing. I can't wait to see how developers iterate on the platform and create really nifty applications. It will also be fun to see what features Apple magically unlocks on the iPad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to try and build some applications now. If you have ideas - let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Musings about femtocells: the futures!</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2010/02/11/musings-about-femtocells-the-futures.html"/>
   <updated>2010-02-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2010/02/11/musings-about-femtocells-the-futures</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;I wrote most of this entry the day before the earthquake in Haiti. It was motivated by the magicJack announcement and my interest in mobile devices within developing nations.  However, the thoughts in this post suddenly seemed more real after I started hearing reports of communication breakdown after the earthquake.&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The femtocell&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the recent CES, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MagicJack&quot;&gt;magicJack company&lt;/a&gt; announced that they wanted to release a consumer grade FemtoCell device as an upgrade to their USB FXO/Softphone device.  Note: magicJack is an insane company. You probably have seen them on television commercials while watching USA 'Up All Night'.  While these commercials almost seem scam-like, they have apparently sold 5 million USB magicJacks.  That's a lot of phone calls!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A femtocell device is basically a mini GSM/CDMA tower. Think of it as a wi-fi AP but instead of wi-fi - it is GSM. You could drop it into your house, plug it into the Internet, and suddenly get 5 bars of connectivity on your mobile handset - instead of the standard AT&amp;amp;T 1 bar. magicJack is offering the same service the USB dongle provides (unlimited calling and what not), but for mobile phones.  As a consumer, you would need to configure your handset to use the magicJack femtocell to receive/send calls.  When you are in range of the device (w/ signal strength enough to cover ~3000 sq. ft. house), you would bypass your carrier and use the magicJack for all incoming and outgoing calls. AWESOME.  Especially with the likes of Google Voice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are questions on the legality of such a device - but it is apparently legal to use inside your residence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Side note: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?q=magicjack+sip&quot;&gt;Magicjack is SIP&lt;/a&gt;. And &lt;a href=&quot;http://magicjackhacks.com/&quot;&gt;hackable&lt;/a&gt;. There is a cat and mouse game being played out trying to unlock it.  You can even use it with &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Asterisk_(PBX)&quot;&gt;Asterisk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The thoughts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I began to think.  Femtocells could be used to open up mobile VOIP.  One scenario is that you could jump on a 3rd party carrier for a limited time to make a p2p VOIP call using your current GSM/WCDMA mobile device.  That is really awesome.  More importantly, what's REALLY awesome is the pirate (3rd party) carriers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine purchasing 100 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2010/01/17/i-love-phones-designed-for-developing-countries/&quot;&gt;Motorola F3&lt;/a&gt;'s, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gnu_radio&quot;&gt;GNU Radio USRP2&lt;/a&gt; (~$1400) running the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OpenBTS&quot;&gt;OpenBTS stack&lt;/a&gt; and a super huge antenna - and suddenly becoming a rural/developing country mobile provider. Or - if you're more interested in being a pirate carrier - you could run this setup in a city and be a carrier for the dark side (drugs, gangs, nerds...). This inexpensive setup is available (and achievable) today!  In case of the apocalypse/disaster/camping/nerdcamp - I think it would be nice to have a set up to deploy to organize/help people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mind started to work into overtime.  I began thinking about the ramifications of hacking the magicJack. Wouldn't it be neat to use femtocell technology to distribute ad hoc mobile carriers around a neighborhood/disaster area/rural/developing country?  You could hook the magicJack femtocell up to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FON#Fonera_2.0n&quot;&gt;Fon2 device (usb/linux/broadband)&lt;/a&gt; and distribute them around in places with connectivity. All you would need is a better antenna and some software to manage the provisioning and device identification. BAM! Instant pirate P2P GSM carrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am hoping that this type of convergence will lead us &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0088763/&quot;&gt;to the future&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I love phones designed for developing countries. </title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2010/01/17/i-love-phones-designed-for-developing-countries.html"/>
   <updated>2010-01-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2010/01/17/i-love-phones-designed-for-developing-countries</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Nokia 1100 and Motorola F3 by nata2, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/natatwo/4283555038/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4039/4283555038_a798542c5f_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nokia 1100 and Motorola F3&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;218&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love mobile phones. I don't know why - but mobile devices represent so much of what I love about technology. The ubiquity, the fascination, all the new technology that pops up and all the different way people use their devices. I also feel like mobile devices will be the future of whatever the internet turns out to be. They will power the internet. With all this in mind - I have started to become interested in the devices that fill the opposite niche. The devices that are SO simple that their are almost NO features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are not Razrs, or other shitty mobile devices which act like they have all sorts of amazing features.  These specific phones are single feature, cheap devices and are often deployed in developing countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two that I really enjoy and I suggest checking out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nokia_1100&quot;&gt;Nokia 1100&lt;/a&gt;. Also known as my favorite phone in the world. I first saw this phone while working for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/natatwo/sets/72057594078282161/&quot;&gt;a minute in Bangalore&lt;/a&gt;. It was advertised as a phone &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://knowledge.wharton.upenn.edu/india/article.cfm?articleid=4358&quot;&gt;made for india&lt;/a&gt;&quot; and apparently was hardy enough to be used by the working class there. I was drawn to the device. I neeeeeded it. It's weird, because at the time I was running a symbian device that supported about every possible feature available in mobile - so thinking about jumping to a mobile device that was pretty much featureless was crazy. But - I was compelled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone isn't that fancy. It has very few features. It is super tiny and is super cheap. It is just a basic, simple phone that does nothing more than look &quot;Nokia&quot; and probably makes calls. The features it has are incredibly handy: flashlight, alarm clock and sms messaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn't realize it then, but the Nokia 1100 is possibly the most popular electronic device in the world. According to the infallible wikipedia: Nokia has sold ~200 million of the Nokia 1100s since it's launch in 2003. To put it in perspective - there have been ~30MM iPhones sold and ~50MM Razrs sold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I eventually got a couple of these and used them as lenders, experiments and generaly fucking around phones. I even sent one to my brother for him to use - which he eventually washed in a washing machine - it still boots. They are HARDY. and 20 bucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second phone that I am interested in is a bit newer and is  a bit more tech. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Motorola_FONE_F3&quot;&gt;Motorola F3&lt;/a&gt;. My buddy &lt;a href=&quot;http://thinkmoreinc.wordpress.com/2009/03/19/50-2/&quot;&gt;Hemmant showed it to me&lt;/a&gt;, told me a bit about the history and I couldn't stop thinking about it. Anecdotally, this phone was made by a Motorola team in india - again for use in the developing countries market. It is simple, has no features (even less than the 1100) and is JUST a phone. There is one major differentiator. The Motorola f3 is one of the only phones to have an e-ink display. This means that it uses very little power in standby (standby time of ~17 days), can be used in low light/no light situations and is rather resilient. The phone didn't sell as many as the Nokia 1100 - in fact it was a veritable failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The F3 has no features. It barely send txt messages. It has voice prompts for all menus. It is just a phone. A user serviceable, easy to charge, thin, e-ink phone. It works well making calls and receiving txt messages. The F3 would be an amazing phone for a child, elderly person or someone who doesn't want to deal with learning pesky features. I got one for my &quot;go bag&quot; as an emergency phone (I am not a survivalist, I just crush a lot).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find an unlocked &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B0013A7KMW?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nata2productions&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B0013A7KMW&quot;&gt;Motorola f3 for about 30 bucks on amazon&lt;/a&gt;. I suggest you get one.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>2009 Hosting Summary (or where does Harper host in 2009/2010)</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2009/12/09/2009-hosting-summary-or-where-does-harper-host-in-20092010.html"/>
   <updated>2009-12-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2009/12/09/2009-hosting-summary-or-where-does-harper-host-in-20092010</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;this is mount fuji by nata2, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/natatwo/2581673203/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3192/2581673203_d18270a494_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;this is mount fuji&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;2009 was an awesome year. A lot of amazing things happened in the world of hosting (and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2009/10/07/leaving-threadless/&quot;&gt;a lot happened&lt;/a&gt; in the world of Harper too). Being a crazy hosting aficionado, I will summarize my thoughts on hosting in 2009 (I will leave the predictions for 2010).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;: I am paid money by Rackspace to think about these things. However, I am an equal opportunity hosting consumer. I will try and be as open as possible (but probably a bit biased as well). This is on my personal blog and does not represent Rackspace in the least. These opinions are mine and do not represent Rackspace in anyway.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I guess I will go ahead and jump in. This is based on what I use and would most likely suggest if we were drinking beers and talking about hosting. Your mileage may vary. I am sorry if I end up causing a nuclear war based on these recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Platforms&quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two platforms are really getting me going these days. Google's App Engine and Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;App Engine is known by my close friends as my true love (haha. second only to &lt;a href=&quot;http://hiromiusagi.com&quot;&gt;my lovely wife&lt;/a&gt;). I spend almost 90% of my development time hacking on App Engine apps (&lt;a href=&quot;http://Excla.im&quot;&gt;Excla.im&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://CityPayments.org&quot;&gt;CityPayments&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://ChicagoAlerts.org&quot;&gt;ChicagoAlerts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://chicagowiki.transitapi.com/&quot;&gt;Transitapi&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://AwesomeUpdater.com&quot;&gt;AwesomeUpdater&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://harpersfriends.com&quot;&gt;Harper's Friends&lt;/a&gt;). App Engine does a few things very well and allows the developer to do the rest. Quite a few of the lessons I learned while scaling out Threadless are baked into the app by default. You don't have to scale all the pieces independently and you can really take care of things all at once. I recommend it and use it for prototyping and building new apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Heroku.com&quot;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;! I go to &lt;a href=&quot;http://Heroku.com&quot;&gt;Heroku.com&lt;/a&gt; I spend about 10 minutes &lt;a href=&quot;http://heroku.com/pricing&quot;&gt;playing with sliders, clicking on features&lt;/a&gt; and acting like I am going to deploy an app to their infrastructure. It's awesome. Heroku makes me want to learn ruby frameworks well and build applications fast. It seems that it might be expensive though. I would love to know if people have actually used it in paid production environments (i have only done hackings).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.djangoproject.com&quot;&gt;Django&lt;/a&gt;, Ruby/Rails or JVM languages (I am looking at you &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scala-lang.org/node/1831&quot;&gt;Scala&lt;/a&gt;!) - I highly recommend App Engine or Heroku.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&quot;Cloud&quot; Server Providers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud Servers are amazing things. Usually they are &lt;a href=&quot;http://xen.org/&quot;&gt;XEN&lt;/a&gt; hosted and wrapped by an API or a nice pretty interface. I &amp;lt;3 them. If I would have had these server options in 2001 I would have been able to make the server kingdom I dreamt about. It would be awesome. Luckily, now in 2009/2010 I can build my server kingdom in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nepholologist.com/&quot;&gt;CLOUDS&lt;/a&gt;. Anyway....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slicehost.com/&quot;&gt;Slicehost&lt;/a&gt; is my favorite. I really enjoy the user interface. I prefer websites with less buttons. Slicehost delivers. However, it doesn't explicitly have usage based billing (pay per hour) - which is why i am also excited about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rackspacecloud.com/cloud_hosting_products/servers&quot;&gt;Rackspace Cloud Servers&lt;/a&gt;. Rackspace Cloud is everything you need to have fun with servers and host enterprise apps. My most recent Cloud server was used to pop up a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ubuntugeek.com/howto-configure-pptp-vpn-in-ubuntu-intrepid-and-jaunty.html&quot;&gt;VPN&lt;/a&gt; in Ubuntu so I could use public wifi without being frightened. It took about 10 minutes from deciding to do it, to connecting with my macbook pro. awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aws.amazon.com/ec2/&quot;&gt;EC2&lt;/a&gt; is pretty sweet as well. It is the heavy duty infrastructure that powers so many awesome sites. I really like watching what Amazon is doing. Amazing stuff. I am super excited about booting from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://aws.amazon.com/ebs/&quot;&gt;EBS&lt;/a&gt;. However, I don't like the complexity that comes with EC2 by default. Which is why I only use EC2 if I need AWS specific utilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidenote: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linode.com/?r=1762fce92f905a07a8623481199299b3ab8a90b9&quot;&gt;Linode&lt;/a&gt; is getting a lot of buzz based on their &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.linode.com/2009/12/04/linode-stomps-competition-in-performance-benchmark/&quot;&gt;performance/cost ratio&lt;/a&gt;. I recommend you &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linode.com/?r=1762fce92f905a07a8623481199299b3ab8a90b9&quot;&gt;take a look&lt;/a&gt; at them and see if they will work for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do find yourself in the dark world of cloud servers, you should check out my favorite utility for managing all things servers: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cloudkick.com/&quot;&gt;CloudKick&lt;/a&gt;. CloudKick is a pretty solid app that allows you manage your all your Rackspace and Amazon servers. You can do it very easily and with very few buttons (I love a small amount of buttons).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for awesome easy servers - use Rackspace Cloud Servers. If you are looking for a full stack (load balancer, block storage and what not) - use Amazon. I use Rackspace Cloud Servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File Hosting and Serving.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;File hosting is simple stuff. I follow this simple guideline:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to host a file for everyone (i.e. a popular image, a iso, download etc) where performance is important - use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rackspacecloud.com/cloud_hosting_products/files&quot;&gt;Rackspace Cloud Files&lt;/a&gt; with limelight integration. This is the closest you will come to paying for enterprise CDN capabilities for a tiny amount of money. You can't beat the level of performance that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.limelightnetworks.com/&quot;&gt;limelight&lt;/a&gt; offers (unless you want to pay for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.akamai.com&quot;&gt;Akamai&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to put a BUNDLE of files somewhere that needs to be public or private - use Cloud Files or &lt;a href=&quot;http://aws.amazon.com/s3/&quot;&gt;S3&lt;/a&gt;. Depending entirely on what vendor you like or what API you are most familiar with. I use both for backing up various data from my servers and home (I recommend &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.s3rsync.com/&quot;&gt;s3sync&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/s3fs/&quot;&gt;s3fs&lt;/a&gt; for S3 or &lt;a href=&quot;http://westhoffswelt.de/projects/mossofs.html&quot;&gt;MossoFS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.chmouel.com/2009/09/02/rsync-like-backup-to-rackspace-cloud-file-with-duplicity/&quot;&gt;CloudFiles/Duplicity&lt;/a&gt; for Cloud Files).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi Tenant/Shared Hosting.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shared hosting is such a pain in the ass. ;) I really don't like it. However, I use it because of the price and because of how easy it is to host stuff for friends and others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use two providers regularly for shared hosting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webfaction.com/?affiliate=harper&quot;&gt;Webfaction&lt;/a&gt; is by far my favorite multi tenant hosting company. It is SUPER NERD. They have this unique approach to hosting based on proxying a bunch of servers through apache. This allows you to easily host a django app that has a rails component and a wordpress blog all at the same domain root. You can even compile your own build of whatever flavor of server you like best. Its a great place for prototyping servers and generally having a great time inlinux. Webfaction also has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://forum.webfaction.com/&quot;&gt;developer community&lt;/a&gt; that offers great support. I host most of my personal stuff onWebfaction (this blog, &lt;a href=&quot;http://harperreed.org&quot;&gt;harperreed.org&lt;/a&gt;, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rackspacecloud.com/cloud_hosting_products/sites&quot;&gt;Rackspace Cloud Sites&lt;/a&gt; is a great multi tenant platform. I use it hosting various apps for your friends and family. It is a no brainer to light up a domain for my brother or friend and have them host it. The only problem I have with Cloud Sites is that sometimes you have to compromise your code to fit in their super scalable infrastructure. You will NEVER go down - but you might have to tweak your drupal or wordpress code to make it easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If file storage is just what you need - then check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dreamhost.com/r.cgi?159982&quot;&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;. For the love of god they have cheap prices. I looked today and they were offering unlimited everything (that doesn't make sense). The only problem is that they don't allow you to use it as a backup service (y&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.labnol.org/internet/backup-files-on-dreamhost-web-hosting-servers/4538/&quot;&gt;ou have to use the space in a very specific way&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enterprise/Physical Servers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enterprise servers are easy. You use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rackspace.com/&quot;&gt;Rackspace&lt;/a&gt;. ;) Seriously though - while at &lt;a href=&quot;http://threadless.com/&quot;&gt;Threadless&lt;/a&gt;, Rackspace saved our asses more than once. Using Rackspace allowed us to concentrate on our application rather than concentrate on our servers. Although they can be expensive - they offer so much that it is often worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are looking for something a bit cheaper or a bit more hands on, I suggest my favorite chicago hosting company: &lt;a href=&quot;http://fdcservers.net/&quot;&gt;FDCServers.net&lt;/a&gt;. They offer great support and cheap servers. You are not going to get near the support that Rackspace offers, but you are going to pay a LOT less. I host a couple big apps at FDC and have had no problems at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wraps up my hosting review. I recommend App Engine, Cloud Servers, Cloudfiles/S3 and Rackspace Managed hosting. heh. See - super easy. All your hosting questions are answered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2010 is going to be an exciting year. I imagine that Rackspace and Amazon will continue to fight head to head. Which will only make us consumers have better options. I also am very excited to see what Google does with App Engine (I imagine that they will NOT be adding &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/googleappengine/issues/detail?id=13&quot;&gt;PHP support&lt;/a&gt;). I hope that 2010 is as productive as 2009 was for hosting, if so - then it will be an exciting, innovative time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leave your questions in the comments - I will attempt to answer them the best i can.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to customize this template</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2009/10/27/how-to-customize-this-template.html"/>
   <updated>2009-10-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2009/10/27/how-to-customize-this-template</id>
   <content type="html">
Nothing here yet.
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to use this template</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2009/10/26/how-to-use-this-template.html"/>
   <updated>2009-10-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2009/10/26/how-to-use-this-template</id>
   <content type="html">
Nothing here yet.
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Leaving Threadless</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2009/10/07/leaving-threadless.html"/>
   <updated>2009-10-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2009/10/07/leaving-threadless</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/techcocktail/2316615921/&quot;&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2411/2316615921_b2cee81590_m.jpg&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I am leaving Threadless after 4 awesome years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was super hard to leave a job that taught me so much, helped me grow and was staffed by all of my friends, but I needed to make that leap towards the future. (&lt;a id=&quot;c8k2&quot; title=&quot;here is a nice interview&quot; href=&quot;http://siliconangle.net/ver2/2009/09/29/exclusive-interview-threadless-cto-harper-reed-heads-to-rackspace-whats-a-nepholologist/&quot;&gt;Here is a nice interview&lt;/a&gt; covering all sorts of aspects of my leaving.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did it, and the future is looking bright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next few months, I am going to be &lt;a id=&quot;vnml&quot; title=&quot;helping Rackspace in their cloud computing division&quot; href=&quot;http://www.rackspacecloud.com/blog/2009/09/30/the-rackspace-cloud-welcomes-harper-reed-nephologist/&quot;&gt;helping Rackspace in their cloud computing division&lt;/a&gt;. My official title is &lt;a href=&quot;http://nepholologist.com/&quot;&gt;Nepholologist&lt;/a&gt;; a person who studies clouds. I will also be working hard to launch a startup (secrets secrets).  This is extremely exciting.  I'll be spending half my day working with amazing technologists at Rackspace and the other half pursuing my own thing.   Rackspace has been amazing.  They've accommodated my want for freedom and the ability to concentrate on my own stuff while helping them out.  It will definitely be the best part-time job I've ever had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on detoxing.  I'll be cleansing my brain of all the assumptions that I formed while at Threadless and ready myself for the startup life.  I want to be more scrappy and lean in my thinking.  Part of the plan is to complete all the various projects that I've worked on throughout the years like &lt;a href=&quot;http://citypayments.org/&quot;&gt;citypayments.org&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://excla.im/&quot;&gt;excla.im&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techcrunch.com/2009/09/12/exclaim-track-track-twitter-search-terms-over-im-in-near-real-time/&quot;&gt;exclaim tracking&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://harpersfriends.com/&quot;&gt;harpersfriends&lt;/a&gt;.  I've done a lot of fun hacks in the last few years, and I want to work on making them much more robust.  This will allow me closure on one chapter of my life - while some doors close, new ones are opening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who was supportive of me in this time. I could never have made this decision without the support of my family and friends.  To my lovely wife Hiromi, who was constantly telling me to pull the trigger.  My friends and coworkers who knew something was up - but dealt with me until the end - even when I was flighty.  My parents who helped me think rationally.  Most importantly, the entire Threadless family.  Without Threadless and the knowledge I've gained from my experiences there, I would not have the opportunities I have today.  The last four years have been utterly amazing (and awesome).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a couple of posts lined up for later this week.  One about my history at Threadless and another about the hijinks that have existed over the last few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned.  It's only just beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My thoughts on the kindle: 1 vs 2 and the iphone app</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2009/03/08/my-thoughts-on-the-kindle.html"/>
   <updated>2009-03-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2009/03/08/my-thoughts-on-the-kindle</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;Kindle2 vs Kindle1 front powered on by nata2, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/natatwo/3307240832/&quot;&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;right&quot; class=&quot;alignright&quot; src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3429/3307240832_8913af9d4f_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Kindle2 vs Kindle1 front powered on&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;First things first&lt;strong&gt;: The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00154JDAI?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nata2productions&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00154JDAI&quot;&gt;Kindle&lt;/a&gt; is awesome&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read a lot. I am not like those crazy people who read a book a day or anything, but i have been reading up to about 2 books a week for the past few years. They are not crazy books, mostly science fiction and fantasy, but they are not small books. I read to chill out. My day pattern is to go to work, work, get home, nap, hang out with hiromi, play computer and then read until i fall alseep. The reading part is VERY important to get my mind and body to a place where I can actually sleep. Needless to say, I take my reading seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ordered an original Kindle way back when they first came out. I was back-ordered for quite awhile. It was enough time for me to question whether or not I would like the device. Luckily, my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://edithfrost.com/&quot;&gt;edith&lt;/a&gt; was also in the same place - she and i chatted incessantly about what the future would be like with the Kindle. It was a bright future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ended up getting it around mid january 08. The first book I read was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000PAAH3A?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nata2productions&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000PAAH3A&quot;&gt;Terror by Dan Simmons&lt;/a&gt;. That is a serious business book. I had started the hardcover of the book earlier in the month and finished it on the kindle. That was my test. It was successful. Although i hated the fact that kindle pages and paper pages don't really line up - the experience was the same. I was able to read fast and was able to forget about the buttons and terrible design of the kindle (like &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/zachklein/status/1192280043&quot;&gt;Zach Klein said&lt;/a&gt; - it looked like the consumer electronics version of the Pontiac Aztec).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Terror, I read the appropriate &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000FBJCKI?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nata2productions&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000FBJCKI&quot;&gt;Diamond Age by Neal Stephenon&lt;/a&gt;. I felt that I was closer to the &quot;Young Lady's Illustrated Primer&quot; than I had been before. I was reading books on an electronic device that was hardy, easy to use and quick. I was able to give it a seemingly unlimited amount of content and could use it for quite some time without a battery change. Like I said above - it is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around this time I discovered the dark and scary underworld that is ebooks on the internet. There is an &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.mobileread.com/wiki/Main_Page&quot;&gt;awesome community of people surrounding ebooks&lt;/a&gt;. They are involved with liberating DRM'd ebooks, converting from one format to another, uploading mass libraries of free ebooks, cataloging ebooks, etc etc. It is awesome. If you are interested in free content - there is an almost unlimited amount of &lt;a href=&quot;http://feedbooks.com/&quot;&gt;free&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gutenberg.org/wiki/Main_Page&quot;&gt;content&lt;/a&gt; that is compatible with the Kindle available online. There is also an unlimited amount of pirated books too. They are harder to find and I feel terrible when I find them (I apparently would rather pay authors than musicians. hah). One thing i noticed while I was experimenting with ebooks - technical manuals and what not don't render as well as non-technical books. I think it has to do with the number of diagrams and tables. They don't render terribly - but often are not nearly accurate to what i imagine the author intended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How you get the ebooks to the kindle is part of the magic. The kindle has what Amazon like to call the whispernet. It is, as far as i can tell, a sprint EVDO modem built into the device. Amazon uses this to wirelessly deliver content to your kindle that you buy from amazon.com. Once again - it is awesome. You click on a book in amazon and BAM - its on your kindle. You are not limited to using this JUST for amazon's content. You can do it with your own ebooks as well. All you need to do is register your email address with amazon and then send books to the yourname@kindle.com email address. The books will appear on your kindle for a small cost ($0.10 i think). If you don't want ot pay for it, you can send the content to yourname@free.kindle.com and it will return the book in the kindle format. You can do this .txt, .pdf and .doc files easily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kindle file format is just the .&lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.mobileread.com/wiki/MOBI&quot;&gt;MOBI ebook format&lt;/a&gt;. Which in turn similar to the .PRC ebook format. The Mobi file is a remnant from the Palm days. it is basically the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.mobileread.com/wiki/PDB&quot;&gt;Palm Database format &lt;/a&gt;that was used for various applications on the original palm platform. What this means is that all the ebooks that end in .mobi and .prc are natively compatible with the kindle. If you had purchased books for use with the mobipocket reader (an awesome ebook reader for windows), there is a good chance that they were .mobi files. You can copy those to the documents folder of your kindle (when you plug it in to your computer via USB) and they will show up in the book list without any work. This really opens up your options for cheap or free ebooks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trick then is to figure out how to convert pdf files and what not to well formed, well meta data'd .mobi files. This makes your kindle happy and allows you to continue to sort by author without having your email address be listed as the author.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went a year reading just the Kindle. I read two paper books that were not available in a digital format during this time. It was interesting. I felt as though I needed to work out to lift the heavy hardcover books. The kindle makes you forget how heavy books can be. My arms are now wusses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Kindle 2 was announced, i ordered two of them. One for me and one for Hiromi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kindle 2 is a huge improvement on the Kindle 1. It is thinner, better performing and a bit easier to use. It is not as easy to turn a page - but it is also not as easy to accidentally turn a page either. I like the new design. The optional leather case is amazing. It works VERY well. i was having to remove the leather case from the original when I would read it - i don't have that problem with the new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of small software tweaks that have trickled their way to the Kindle 1 as well. They are separating out your uploaded content from the content that came from directly Amazon. I am also having a hard time finding things that are lost on the kindle. I suppose i could search - but i never think of that when I am looking for content. The interface on the Kindle 2 is much faster. The pages turn faster and the books load faster. The screen is amazing. I really like it. I don't like the fact that I can't easily turn off the wireless with a hardware switch. I liked being able to not interrupt my reading to turn wireless on or off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all - the Kindle 2 is a huge improvment over the Kindle 1. If you are able to upgrade, do it. And then give your original kindle to someone close to you who wants one. That is the best plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hiromi loves hers. I was worried that she wouldn't like it - but it turns out that it works very well for her. She likes the size and the ease of use. She took to it very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got my kindle 2 I was showing a couple of my coworkers some of the data about it. Specifically the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macworld.com/article/138728/2009/02/whispersync.html&quot;&gt;whispersync&lt;/a&gt; stuff. I told them that I wouldn't be surprised if they released an iPhone app that allowed ebook reading on the Kindle. I based this on the success of the Stanza app. I stated to my buddies that I was only confused as to the strategy to release such an app, especially on how it could accidently stifle the Kindle 2 sales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then a couple days later the Kindle app was released. Like the Kindle - it is awesome. hah. With the Kindle app for the iphone and the Kindle, you are able to sync your placemarks on the books you are reading. You could read to a certain point in a novel while on your commute - then go to a meeting and pick up your iphone and continue reading from where you left off on your kindle. Then you coudl pick up the kindle and it would sync to where you left off on the iphone. That is cool. I tried it and it works. It is a bit wonky - but for the most part it works great. The only issue i have with the app is that it doesn't have ANY of the content that you upload via email. It is only amazon purchased content. Lame. I read a lot of &quot;found&quot; books and a lot of purchased books. An example is a series of books where 2-4 are in the amazon kindle store, but book 1 isn't. I find book 1 elsewhere and then buy 2-4. However, I can't read book 1 on my iphone. Only the kindle. WHAT IS THE WORLD COMING TO. ;) I understand amazon's reasoning for this - and I don't expect it to change. I do wish i could push my emailed books into their cloud and handle them a bit better (with metadata, etc). I doubt that will happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you read a lot and want a great reading experience, you should &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00154JDAI?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nata2productions&amp;amp;linkCode=as2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=390957&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B00154JDAI&quot;&gt;buy a kindle.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Python Oauth Client - Excla.im</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2009/02/28/python-oauth-client-exclaim.html"/>
   <updated>2009-02-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2009/02/28/python-oauth-client-exclaim</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I built &lt;a href=&quot;http://excla.im&quot;&gt;Excla.im&lt;/a&gt; quite awhile ago, well before &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/harper&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; unleased their oauth beta program. Regardless, &lt;a href=&quot;http://factoryjoe.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Chris Messina&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/factoryjoe/2841257703/&quot;&gt;tagged the Excla.im sign up process as an anty pattern&lt;/a&gt; within his flickr stream. I was bummed because i would have loved to use Oauth to authenticate Excla.im. But because of the tagging, i was constantly thinking about how to remove the anti pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, Twitter released the &lt;a href=&quot;http://groups.google.com/group/twitter-development-talk/browse_thread/thread/42486bd3d7d136d0/f0e89b742bf0033e?pli=1&quot;&gt;Oauth Beta&lt;/a&gt; and I was able to bribe @&lt;a href=&quot;http://al3x.net/&quot;&gt;Al3x&lt;/a&gt; to give me access (which reminds me, i need to send my &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/natatwo/3149040948/&quot;&gt;bribe&lt;/a&gt;). I then sat for a month looking at the various python examples for OAuth and basically said &quot;What The Fuck&quot; over and over again. There were no solid examples and my experience with OAuth in PHP was a total hack so i could post shit to fireeagle. I was SOL as to finding a guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then &lt;a href=&quot;http://abrah.am&quot;&gt;abrah.am&lt;/a&gt; released his &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/poseurtech/twitteroauth/tree/master)&quot;&gt;PHP twitter OAuth lib&lt;/a&gt;. It worked really well and was pretty much just plug and play to use it in a PHP app. Nice. I wanted that but in python. I decided to spend a minute or two and create it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The base library my client is using is the the &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/gdata-python-client/source/browse/trunk/src/gdata/#gdata/oauth&quot;&gt;OAuth lib&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: none; color: #000000;&quot;&gt;google &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/gdata-python-client/&quot;&gt;gdata-python-client&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/gdata-python-client/&quot;&gt; project&lt;/a&gt;. I figure it is a working client and is in production use - so it should be solid. There are very few &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/gdata-python-client/source/browse/trunk/src/gdata/oauth/CHANGES.txt&quot;&gt;changes&lt;/a&gt; between it and the official client that is released through &lt;a href=&quot;http://oauth.googlecode.com/svn/code/python/oauth/&quot;&gt;oauth.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client is rather simple, in fact it should work with other api providers with very little work. You can check it out at &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/harperreed/twitteroauth-python/&quot;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. Please let me know feedback. i am a python n00b - so give me your best shot/code review. I am using Google Code as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/twitteroauth-python/issues/list&quot;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt;, so feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/twitteroauth-python/issues/entry&quot;&gt;post some bugs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is rather pluggable. I was able to launch excla.im (on app engine) with oauth support in no time. I am currently not holding passwords for anyone. It is an awesome feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Seven Things (goddamn internet friends)</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2009/01/11/seven-things-goddamn-internet-friends.html"/>
   <updated>2009-01-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2009/01/11/seven-things-goddamn-internet-friends</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;I was tagged by both &lt;a href=&quot;http://eliw.wordpress.com/2009/01/05/seven-things/&quot;&gt;Eli White&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://flinglog.com/text/seven-things/&quot;&gt;Brian Fling&lt;/a&gt; in this dastardly meme regarding 7 things. I am usually a HUGE fan of all things meme - and kind of regard myself as a &lt;a href=&quot;http://fukung.net&quot;&gt;certified&lt;/a&gt; meme expert. However this whole meme that requires a lot of work - I.E. blogging is something entirely different. I think i actually like it, but i am not entirely sure yet ;).&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;I do find it hilarious that almost every blog post regarding this seven things starts with a bit of self deprecation and surprise at how this meme stumbled upon innocent them. Well, it did come as a surprise - so I guess i understand.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;Well here it goes. Seven things about me:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;I grew up without a TV. When I was quite young (~3) my parents got rid of their TV. I am not completely sure why. I imagine it had something to do with money (the lack of) and priorities being making sure my brother and I were clothed and fed. My parents got their first TV after getting rid of the previous one when I was about 21. My parents used to rent a TV for big events (war, olympics, etc) and my brother and I would watch the TV manically until it was returned to the rental place. We also used to rent a TV and VCR about once or twice a year to watch all the movies we could in the time alloted. Those were awesome times. I currently don't have a TV.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;I have been paid to YoYo and Juggle in front of a LOT of people. I guess that makes me a professional. Heh. In college my two best buddies (&lt;a href=&quot;http://therats.org&quot;&gt;Matiss&lt;/a&gt; and Brian) and myself started a &quot;circus&quot; group. We juggled and did shows for all sorts of things. We opened for &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Incubus_(band)&quot;&gt;Incubus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sir_Mix_A_Lot&quot;&gt;Sir Mix A Lot&lt;/a&gt;, and a few other boring bands. We protest juggled as a group called Jugglers against homophobia - protesting people like &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Elizabeth_Dole&quot;&gt;Elizabeth Dole&lt;/a&gt; and her homophobic antics. After college I continued to support my friends by juggling on the side. It was a really fun time. I don't juggle as much as i would like, but i still try to make it to conventions and what not. It is a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;My first computer was an Apple ][c. My dad got it in some trade. My brother and I would build text games in basic. Shortly after that I got in to BBSs. Mostly we called places like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.totse.com/&quot;&gt;&amp;amp;totse&lt;/a&gt; and downloaded things that would get me in trouble. It was an awesome time. I suggest checking out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbsdocumentary.com/&quot;&gt;BBS Documentary&lt;/a&gt; to get an idea of how awesome it actually was.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Four:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;I met my lovely wife &lt;a href=&quot;http://hiromiusagi.com&quot;&gt;Hiromi&lt;/a&gt; while in college in iowa. We moved to Chicago together in 2001 to live together as roommates. Eventually, it became clear that our relationship was much more than that. We got married in 2006 and happily live in Chicago. She is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Five:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;I read a lot. I always have. Growing up without a TV will do that to a person. I read mostly fiction, but will stray to the dark side and read non-fiction every once and awhile. I usually read about an hour before going to bed. It helps calm me down and is a good way for me to get into the sleeping groove. I have recently been into ebooks and use a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B000FI73MA?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;tag=nata2productions&amp;amp;link_code=as3&amp;amp;camp=211189&amp;amp;creative=373489&amp;amp;creativeASIN=B000FI73MA&quot;&gt;Amazon Kindle&lt;/a&gt; to read them. I find that I do miss regularly reading paper books, but the convenience of reading ebooks is awesome. I can't wait until the eInk displays and associated readers are smaller, easier to use and cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Six:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;I love David Bowie. It isn't a love that requires posters and discussion or anything. It is kind of similar to how people who grew up catholic talk about religion. David Bowie has just always been there for me. My first record I picked for myself was &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Rise_and_Fall_of_Ziggy_Stardust_and_the_Spiders_from_Mars&quot;&gt;Ziggy Stardust&lt;/a&gt;. My first concert was the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sound_and_Vision_Tour&quot;&gt;Bowie's Sound + Vision tour&lt;/a&gt;. When I was quite younger, my mom took me to get my hair cut and I brought along my &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Labyrinth_(film)&quot;&gt;Labyrinth&lt;/a&gt; LP to show the stylist that I wanted &lt;a href=&quot;http://thefanboys.com/wp-content/uploads/2006/11/david_bowie_labyrinth.jpg&quot;&gt;David Bowie hair&lt;/a&gt;. I ended up with a rat tail.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Seven:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;Although I always knew I would end up with a Computer Science degree - I fought it as long as I could. In college I studied the history of Catholicism for a couple years before actually jumping into computer science. It was awesome. I ended up concentrating on &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Giordano_Bruno&quot;&gt;Giordano Bruno&lt;/a&gt; and the his (untimely) multi-world theory. It was a lot of fun and lead me to have an unnatural interest in the mechanics of theology.&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;ol style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That's it!
&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;To make this official, I now have to tag 7 people to make a Seven Things list on their blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;Ready? These Seven People please report to the meme office and make a Seven Things entry on your blog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dylanreed.com&quot;&gt;Dylan Reed&lt;/a&gt; - my brother - I like involving him in the blogosphere.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://morefishthanman.com/&quot;&gt;Scott Van Den Plas&lt;/a&gt; - crazy person - He has a great blog and I love including him in meme parties.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.localkinegrinds.com/&quot;&gt;Ryan Kanno&lt;/a&gt; - hawaii nerd - Ryan is hilarious. Hopefully all seven things will be about a Ukulele.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://prestosamo.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Cole Pierce&lt;/a&gt; - art nerd - Cole is one of my favorite artists. I used to make him go to terrible iowan raves.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lakshvivek.com/&quot;&gt;Lakshmi Nagarajan&lt;/a&gt; - friend and pro blogger - Lakshmi is an awesome &quot;mommy&quot; blogger who learned to drive a car in 2008. heh.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://anders.conbere.org/journal/&quot;&gt;Anders Conbere&lt;/a&gt; - xmpp nerd - Anders is awesome. I hope he picks this meme up.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joevw.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Speedy Joe&lt;/a&gt; - awesome designer - Speedy just set up his blog. I wanted to give him some blogosphere love. ;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;The rules of this ‘game’ for those that I have tagged:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Link your original tagger(s), and list these rules on your blog.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Share seven facts about yourself in the post - some random, some weird.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tag seven people at the end of your post by leaving their names and the links to their blogs.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Let them know they’ve been tagged by leaving a comment on their blogs and/or Twitter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;clear: both&quot;&gt;There yea have it. I continued the meme. I am not one to be a meme killer ;) This was fun. Thanks to Eli and Brian for making it happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;br class=&quot;final-break&quot; style=&quot;clear: both&quot; /&gt;

</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>2008 Retrospective</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2009/01/04/2008-retrospectiv.html"/>
   <updated>2009-01-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2009/01/04/2008-retrospectiv</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;2008 was a great year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of fun things happened. I started speaking more. I started using linux as my desktop. Obama won. I played with XMPP manically. I built some neat applications and Threadless continued to be awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my blog, the following entires got a decent amount of attention:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2008/10/06/chicago-transit-api/&quot;&gt;Chicago Transit API&lt;/a&gt; - Oct. 6th - Reverse engineered and built a proxy for the CTA Bustracker.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2008/08/30/mini-hi-fi-the-chase/&quot;&gt;Mini Hi Fi: The Chase&lt;/a&gt; - Aug. 30th - Built a mini stereo. Audiophile addiction avoided!&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2008/07/13/exclaim-a-replacement-jabber-bot/&quot;&gt;Excla.im - a replacement jabber bot&lt;/a&gt; - Jul. 13th - Built a small jabber bot to update twitter.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2008/03/25/social-xmpp/&quot;&gt;Social XMPP&lt;/a&gt; - Mar. 25th - Initiated a conversation with the venerable Peter St. Andre to start up the social xmpp list.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2008/03/02/olpc-chicago-jabber-server/&quot;&gt;OLPC Chicago Jabber Server&lt;/a&gt; - Mar. 2nd - Built a jabber server for hosting various OLPC related community activities.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2008/03/02/awesome-hosting-options/&quot;&gt;Awesome Hosting Options&lt;/a&gt; - Mar. 2nd - Outlined what I use for hosting. A rather popular post. A bit outdated. I need to update it.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2008/02/29/the-mosso-cloud-how-requests-are-not-a-good-metric/&quot;&gt;The Mosso Cloud: Requests are not a good metric&lt;/a&gt; - Feb. 29th - I was unhappy with how mosso had set about charging us for usage. Mosso is still a good host and is still struggling with this issue.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2008/02/25/google-apps-auth-xmpp-and-radius-idea/&quot;&gt;Google Apps Auth: XMPP and Radius idea&lt;/a&gt; - Feb. 25th - I wrote about how I wanted a radius endpoint for my google apps account. It would make a bunch of stuff easier for me. My solution was to hack a radius server to auth over our Google Apps talk/XMPP account.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2008/01/22/putting-the-blame-on-your-vendors-for-the-win/&quot;&gt;Putting the blame on your vendors for the win&lt;/a&gt;. - Jan. 22nd - I was unhappy with how some internet peers had blamed their vendor when equipment failures resulted in downtime. I think that people should stand behind their decisions and if there is an error - they should take responsibilities. It is weak to blame a vendor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The theme seemed to be XMPP and Hosting - which, if you have hung out with me recently,  is rather close to what i like to talk about in real life ;). I think that I will continue this trend into 2009, but hopefully blog about it more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did notice that I ended up blogging less this year than almost any year before (2008: 30 entries, 2007: 84 entries, 2006: 154 entries, 2005: 166 entries, 2004: 275 entries, 2003: 290 entries, 2002: 266 entries, 2001: 103 entries, 2000: 27 entries). I have been blogging for about 8 years for a  total of about 1395 entries - which means that this 1 year accounts for about ~2% of my blog entries. haha. I am guessing that 2% accounts for about 90% of my blog traffic. I am not a new years resolution type of guy, but I would like to blog more regularly. Hopefully get my percentage up a bit. maybe 100 posts. It isn't THAT hard. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To offset the lack of blogging, I twittered a lot. In fact, I updated twitter around 3251 times (this number is approximate because of the twitter api and paging). Of the 3251 tweets, 852 were replies. I replied to &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/paulsmith&quot;&gt;paulsmith&lt;/a&gt; the most with 25 replies. &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/ryankanno&quot;&gt;ryankanno&lt;/a&gt; was second with 20 replies. I said awesome around 249 times. I talked about sleep 71 times. I mentioned Hiromi 122 times. I said fuck about 46 times. I talked about work 238 times.  My fake new years resolution about twitter is to stop having twitter steal blog entries. I saw that written somewhere and I laughed at how often that happens. I think of a blog and instead just twitter about it. It kills the entry and doesn't flesh out my thoughts as much. I think the best plan is to integrate and use both mediums to develop a post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My flickr usage dropped significantly this year. Kind of a bummer because i LOVE taking pictures. Hiromi is currently telling me that we don't take enough picture together.  It looks like i took only ~800 pictures in 2008. I blame this on the iPhone and how slow its camera is. In previous years i have used &lt;a href=&quot;http://shozu.com&quot;&gt;shozu&lt;/a&gt; and a 360 device. This let me upload picture directly after i took them and most often in the background. I need to take more pictures. I wish i had more insight into my flickr pictures. I need to build out my archive a bit more to keep track of everything like i did with twitter. It is quite handy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work was awesome in 2008. We had some large projects that launched a bit rougher than i would have liked, but they turned out awesome. &lt;a href=&quot;http://typetees.com&quot;&gt;Typetees.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://theselectseries.com&quot;&gt;theselectseries.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://threadlesskids.com&quot;&gt;threadlesskids.com&lt;/a&gt; and the new &lt;a href=&quot;http://threadless.com&quot;&gt;threadless.com&lt;/a&gt; are all awesome. The team that worked on them are all amazing. I couldn't ask for a better team of technologists, production people, operations people and warehouse people to help make technology at Threadless be awesome.  I can't wait to see what is in the pipeline for 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously - 2008 was a great year. I can't wait to see what 2009 brings. I hope more fun, more blog entires, more tweets and more pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Happy Holidays</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/12/26/happy-holidays.html"/>
   <updated>2008-12-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/12/26/happy-holidays</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;It's snowing like crazy. by nata2, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/natatwo/3119262443/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright&quot; src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3117/3119262443_bf1b6529b3_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;It's snowing like crazy.&quot; width=&quot;180&quot; height=&quot;240&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Hello everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been busy. Threadless just ended its &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threadless.com/news/400348/Tees_from_5_at_Threadless_Annual_Holiday_Sale&quot;&gt;annual holiday sale&lt;/a&gt; (went out with a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threadless.com/news/406990/And_the_final_gift_is_opened_to_reveal&quot;&gt;bang&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;a href=&quot;http://hiromiusagi.com&quot;&gt;Hiromi&lt;/a&gt; and I have been busy getting read for our holiday party with my parents on christmas (today!) and i have been hacking on a bunch of stuff in my spare time. Hiromi made an amazing dinner and we ate it. ;) It was a great time. We missed &lt;a href=&quot;http://dylanreed.com&quot;&gt;Dylan&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://photodork.org/&quot;&gt;Sarah&lt;/a&gt;, but we will hopefully see them soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year has been great thus far and I will attempt to memorialize it in a year end post around the 1st. However, in the meantime I wanted to take a moment and say &quot;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threadless.com/product/509/HI&quot;&gt;HI&lt;/a&gt;&quot; and go ahead and wish everyone a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Holiday_greetings&quot;&gt;Happy Holidays&lt;/a&gt;. I hope everyone discovered their proper amount of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Conspicuous_consumption&quot;&gt;conspicuous consumer&lt;/a&gt;. I know that &lt;a href=&quot;http://reedbooks.org/&quot;&gt;we&lt;/a&gt; did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although, I certainly don't update my blog quite as often as I would like (or my mom would like) - I do update my &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/harper&quot;&gt;twitter status&lt;/a&gt; quite often and post a &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/natatwo&quot;&gt;number of pictures to flickr&lt;/a&gt;. I am hopefully going to start updating this blog a bit more, but in the meantime you are welcome to check out my &lt;a href=&quot;http://harperreed.org/activity/&quot;&gt;interweb activity aggregation page&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://feeds.feedburner.com/HarperReedsActivityDigest&quot;&gt;associated RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; (props to &lt;a href=&quot;http://derek.broox.com&quot;&gt;broox&lt;/a&gt; who showed me &lt;a href=&quot;http://derek.broox.com/today&quot;&gt;his&lt;/a&gt;, which I copied).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Release your applications inner API. Please.</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/10/06/release-your-applications-inner-api-please.html"/>
   <updated>2008-10-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/10/06/release-your-applications-inner-api-please</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have recently been involved in talking to a local chicago entity about their unofficial API. It has been fun and deserves a blog entry of its own. However, this is not that blog entry - this blog entry is about mashups and the not so public APIs they often create.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past couple years i have constantly been tearing apart webapps. Either because I wearing my developer hat at work or because i am rocking on something at home. I have always been trying to figure out what goes on behind the scenes and wondering if i coudl use that to do something cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks ago i decided to figure out what powered the CTA Bustracker Google Maps mash up and was able to expose the &lt;a href=&quot;http://chicago.transitapi.com/&quot;&gt;&quot;hidden&quot; api that powered the mashup&lt;/a&gt;. In a conversation I had with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.juggernautco.com/about.html&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-family: Georgia,Times New Roman,Times,serif; font-size: x-small;&quot;&gt;Dan x O'Neil&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; about the unofficial API I was able to expose - he asked a question about mashups and APIs. It led me to rant about how there is so much untapped APIs out on the internet currently powering mashups, and other rich internet appliances. These APIs are not documented, are unofficial and will of course change. But think of the data and functionality that could come from all these mashups and startups who are building an API for internal use but could release it and empower their users to build something neat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have built an application recently that has endpoints that is returning JSON for js frontend work, or is integrating with google maps, or is exposing endpoints for fun - PLEASE, please document it a bit, throw an API link on your site and let some enterprising and bored nerds build something on the thing you made. Don't try to imagine how someone would use your endpoints - but expect to be surprised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to do this with threadless - we built it to be very easy to break down and integrate into other peoples sites (image urls, etc). But, there is a secret API that we should be releasing, documenting and letting people use. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Chicago Transit API</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/10/06/chicago-transit-api.html"/>
   <updated>2008-10-06T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/10/06/chicago-transit-api</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;The goddamn damon bus. seriously by nata2, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/natatwo/264290817/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright&quot; src=&quot;http://farm1.static.flickr.com/87/264290817_f5ccf294d0_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The goddamn damon bus. seriously&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I have been working hard to release the work that I have been doing to expose some of the more interesting real time data about chicago transit. Currently it is very bus-centric, but that is hopefully changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The genesis for this API is some work I did awhile ago reverse engineering the &lt;a href=&quot;http://ctabustracker.com/bustime/map/displaymap.jsp&quot;&gt;CTA Bus Tracker mashup&lt;/a&gt;. I was able to expose the endpoints that powered their google maps mashup. In its original state - you can get some pretty awesome functionality and data. I am attempting to clean it up and make it more robust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The native endpoints thus far are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://chicago.transitapi.com/bustime/map/getRoutePoints.jsp?route=49&quot;&gt;getRoutePoints&lt;/a&gt;: Returns latitude/longitude, stop IDs, and stop names for bus stops along a particular route.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://chicago.transitapi.com/bustime/map/getPatternPoints.jsp?route=20&amp;amp;pattern=959&quot;&gt;getPatternPoints&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://chicago.transitapi.com/bustime/map/getStopPredictions.jsp?stop=8207&amp;amp;route=49&quot;&gt;getStopPredictions&lt;/a&gt;: Gets stop predictions. Timing and whatnot.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://chicago.transitapi.com/bustime/map/getBusPredictions.jsp?bus=6654&quot;&gt;getBusPredictions&lt;/a&gt;: Returns arrival predictions for a particular bus.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://chicago.transitapi.com/bustime/map/getBusesForRoute.jsp?route=49&quot;&gt;getBusesForRoute&lt;/a&gt;: Gets buses for specific route&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://chicago.transitapi.com/bustime/map/getBusesForRouteAll.jsp&quot;&gt;getBusesForRouteAll&lt;/a&gt;: Gets information about every bus in the system.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://chicago.transitapi.com/bustime/map/schedules.jsp?agency=1&amp;amp;route=92&quot;&gt;Schedule&lt;/a&gt;: Download the Schedule (pdf! w00t)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://chicago.transitapi.com/bustime/map/getTimeAndTemp.jsp&quot;&gt;getTimeAndTemp&lt;/a&gt;: Outputs the current time and temp&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I have created a proxy for the endpoints that will do some caching and hopefully alleviate any crazy load the CTA servers would have if this API becomes popular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also did some work to push the UPOC alerts from the CTA riders community into a usable form. That endpoint is the first of hopefully many that can be used to grab real time information about the CTA. You can access it at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://chicago.transitapi.com/api/alerts/upoc/latest/&quot;&gt;Community Upoc alerts&lt;/a&gt;: Outputs the last alert sent from the UPOC group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Dan X O'Neil and myself hacked these alerts into the &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/ctatweet&quot;&gt;CTA Tweet bot&lt;/a&gt; that sends CTA updates via twitter. Pretty neat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward with the API, I want to do a couple key things. The first is to return JSON instead of that terrible XML. The second is to create a couple endpoints that will help with finding the right bus at the right location. I am always looking for help with this stuff - so if you have any ideas - please let me know in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, there are not a whole lot of applications using this API. The only ones I have thus far are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://commuting.in/chicago/about&quot;&gt;Commuting.in Chicago&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://txtful.com/template.html?templateId=1368034&quot;&gt;txtful bus alerts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://businfo.chicagobus.org/&quot;&gt;ChicagoBus.org Bus Finder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If you know of any others - let me know. I have a couple projects brewing myself that will hopefully add a shortcode, and a jabber bot for bus notifications and queries. Are there any things yall would like to see? I personally want a really solid native iphone app. It would be awesome to be able to have the iphone pinpoint your location and then tell you what the nearest buses are that are arriving soon. Also - replicating the bus tracker in an easier to use fashion would be excellent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of this API work wouldn't have been possible without the help of &lt;a href=&quot;http://detour1999.com&quot;&gt;Dylan Richard&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.derivativeworks.com/&quot;&gt;Dan X O'Neil&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://chicagobus.org&quot;&gt;Kevin Zolkiewicz&lt;/a&gt;. The CTA has also been amazingly cool with all of this - I really like those guys.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mini Hi Fi: The Chase</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/08/30/mini-hi-fi-the-chase.html"/>
   <updated>2008-08-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/08/30/mini-hi-fi-the-chase</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;2008-08-27 00:32:37 -0500 by nata2, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/natatwo/2802479942/&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright&quot; src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3048/2802479942_2895dcc1d2_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My System&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Anyone who hung out with me in the last couple months has probably heard me rant and roll about my new stereo. It is awesome. I can't shut up about it. I am addicted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all started a couple years ago when the SI Tripath Amp emerged on the market. It was a little amp that was reviewed as being MUCH bigger than its cost or its physical size. It was about 40 bucks at target and reviewed the same as amps costing thousands more. Pretty sweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I purchased a couple of these and immediately blew at least 2 of them fucking around, recasing and generally attempting to make them sound better than they sound stock. After giving my final one away to a former coworker of Hiromi's - I stopped paying attention to the various blogs and audio reviews of the T Amps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until about 1.5 months ago. heh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read an article about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hackaday.com/2008/07/27/build-your-own-speakers/&quot;&gt;building speakers on hackaday&lt;/a&gt;. It lead me to another article about building your own &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hackaday.com/2005/05/26/cat-5-speaker-cables/&quot;&gt;speaker hi-end cables&lt;/a&gt;. Which lead me to an article about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tnt-audio.com/clinica/t-amp_tweaks_e.html&quot;&gt;reboxing a SI T-Amp&lt;/a&gt;. Full circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The T-Amp article lead me to start reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://diyaudio.com/&quot;&gt;diyaudio.com&lt;/a&gt; for about 2 weeks straight. It was madness. I stopped programming, stopped hacking stuff and just started building out a new HiFi system in my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read a bunch of reviews about amps, speakers, and all sorts of random topics - until i found this awesome &lt;a href=&quot;http://6moons.com/audioreviews/trends/ta10.html&quot;&gt;6moons review&lt;/a&gt; of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trendsaudio.com/EN/Product/TA-10_desc.htm&quot;&gt;Trends Audio TA-10.1&lt;/a&gt;. The thing that was interesting about this review is that the &lt;a href=&quot;http://6moons.com/audioreviews/trends/ta10_3.html&quot;&gt;3rd page&lt;/a&gt; of the review mentioned some Klipsch speakers that i happen to own and have in my living room. The review mentioned how awesome the TA 10.1 was when matched with the Klipsch speakers, especially in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.canuckaudiomart.com/forum/viewtopic.php?t=7335&quot;&gt;horizontal bi-amping&lt;/a&gt; configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I went ahead and picked up two of them from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.audio-magus.com/&quot;&gt;Audio Magus&lt;/a&gt; to bi-amp my klipsch monsters. I also picked up a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phonopreamps.com/tc754pp.html&quot;&gt;CHEAP preamp&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phonopreamps.com/&quot;&gt;phonopreamps.com&lt;/a&gt;. In total i spent about $325 and picked up 2 amps and 1 preamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After they arrived, i was able to hook everything up and after a bit of burn in really hear how awesome it actually is. I am very happy with the results. I am not going to talk about soundstage or anything like that - just that it sounds awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I am bi-amping my speakers - I went ahead and set both amps as poweramps (by a jumper inside the amp) and am using the preamp as the volume control. This works very well. My only gripe is that there is no remote, but that is a future addition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For audio sources, i have an airport express, my turntable and a poor CD player.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future of this system is exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am planning on getting a solid preamp. Probably a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dared.gr/display.php?lang=EN&amp;amp;model=SL-2000A&quot;&gt;Dared SL 2000A&lt;/a&gt;. It seems that adding a tube preamp to my &quot;digital&quot; amp setup could offer some warmth to the system. It also has a remote for volume control. The only downside is that it only has 2 channels for input - which means that I will have to figure out one source to get rid of (turntable most likely).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing I would like to add is a couple DACs to do the D/A conversion for my Airport Express and my CD transport. I am looking at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.audio-magus.com/Super_Pro_DAC707SE_USB_p/dac707usb.htm&quot;&gt;Super Pro DAC707SE&lt;/a&gt;. It is cheap, well reviewed and has USB support if I choose to add the DAC to one of my computers as a source. Having a DAC should make my Airport Express experience better when listening to lossless audio files. It will also make the shitty CD player sound a lot better. Ultimately, I would like to get a better cd player - which leads me to my next plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CD transport is world is pretty nuts. It seems that every single transport available is in the thousands, and that there isn't any really a DIY CD transport option that is accessible. There is one compelling option for DIY - the Shigaclone. It is a direct clone of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sakurasystems.com/products/shigacd.html&quot;&gt;Shigaraki Transport&lt;/a&gt;, however the insides are from a JVC boombox (&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/JVC-RC-EZ31-Portable-Boombox-Cassette/dp/B000FD2AG4&quot;&gt;JVC RC-EZ31&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.diyaudio.com/forums/showthread.php?threadid=120229&quot;&gt;details are at diyaudio&lt;/a&gt;. Unlike the other clones out there, the Shigaclone seems to be VERY hands on and just a bit past my skill level. I am waiting for a dedicated howto that explains all the various parts of the shigaclone and how I can make one without reading 1800 forum posts. In the meantime, i will have to find an alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alternative I have thus far is a 1994 NEC Multispin CDR-401G external CD-ROM. It has play/pause/forward/back buttons and has a digital coax out. It apparently sounds terrible, however once it is hooked to a DAC, it works wonderfully. It is VERY hard to find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for a CD transport, unless i want to spend a million bucks, I have two choices. Build a clone or buy a vintage CDROM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that the part of this i liked the best is the chase. I am very happy that I have a good sound system, but I am MORE excited about attempting to find the best system for cheap. Its a GREAT game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just need to make sure that i don't fall for the tricks. I don't want to spend ANY money on cables, nor money on speaker wire. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.engadget.com/2008/03/03/audiophiles-cant-tell-the-difference-between-monster-cable-and/4&quot;&gt;Metal is metal.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>oh yea. i have a blog</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/07/13/oh-yea-i-have-a-blog.html"/>
   <updated>2008-07-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/07/13/oh-yea-i-have-a-blog</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apparently for the last month or two, I totally forgot that i have a blog. Instead of blogging, i have been hanging out with Hiromi, using twitter,traveling, programming and building things. I didn't have time to include blogging into that mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a theory, that when my twitter usage goes up, my blogging goes down (I am not &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.problogger.net/archives/2008/07/12/does-twitter-distract-from-or-inspire-your-blogging/&quot;&gt;alone in this&lt;/a&gt;). I am a bit annoyed by this. My twitter posts don't have as much reach as my blog posts. My interaction with people on twitter is much higher than on my blog. I am so conflicted. haha. Luckily, i think i can do both without sacraficing (much) one or the other.I think i will have to just make my posting smaller and more frequent (like a tumble log - but bigger) and make sure that i don't spend myself entirely on twitter.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Japan Tech Friends</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/07/13/japan-tech-friends.html"/>
   <updated>2008-07-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/07/13/japan-tech-friends</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks ago, I was in japan for some family events. It was a great trip. Hanging out with Hiromi's family and friends was awesome. Since we were going to be spending some free time in Tokyo, i decided to reach out to the Tokyo tech community and meet some people.  I emailed my friend, Kristin, who had &lt;a href=&quot;http://kristenicole2.wordpress.com/2008/05/28/day-2-in-tokyo-still-afraid-of-heights/&quot;&gt;just been to Japan&lt;/a&gt; and asked her to hook me up with some cool cats in the tech scene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She obliged and I was able to meet with an awesome group of people for a barcamp like event, and then hang out with another awesome guy who should be the tech tour guide of tokyo. I sadly missed some people from ibm, who were out of town on business - but there is always next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://akimoto.jp/blog/2008/06/21/aa-camp3%E6%97%A5%E9%80%A3%E7%B6%9A%E9%96%8B%E5%82%AC/&quot;&gt;barcamp like event&lt;/a&gt; was called AA-Camp. It was hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://akimoto.jp&quot;&gt;Akky AKIMOTO&lt;/a&gt; who is from &lt;a href=&quot;http://labs.cybozu.co.jp/en/&quot;&gt;Cybozu Labs&lt;/a&gt;. Cybozu labs is a really neat incubator ran by the Cubozu company. It seems that the goal of the lab is to create the next big thing in japanese technology. They give a lot of autonomy to their engineers and really allow them to flouish. The idea of incubators always seem so fun. Akky had two other technologists at the event besides myself. We worked on our own projects, then we presented about ourselves. A&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The presentations were pretty biographical, covering what we were up to, currently working on and our employers. The first to present was &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ganchiku.com/&quot;&gt;Shin Ohno&lt;/a&gt;. He is a developer working with Akky to create a neat site for creating comparison tables called &lt;a href=&quot;http://narabe.com/&quot;&gt;Narabe&lt;/a&gt;. Shin has an awesome plan. He travels and does development from his travels. Since all he needs is internet and a laptop, he is well connected no matter where he finds himself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next presenter was Akky. He ran through his work, cybozu, cybozu labs and some of their applications they have created. They have launched a number of neat applications - my favorite is &lt;a href=&quot;http://mylingual.net/&quot;&gt;mylingual&lt;/a&gt; - which is a firefox script that translates site from one language to another. sweet stuff. The other applications were &lt;a href=&quot;http://pathtraq.com/&quot;&gt;PathTraq&lt;/a&gt; (alexa like site ranking) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://japanize.31tools.com/&quot;&gt;Japanize&lt;/a&gt; (translating sites into japanese), &lt;a href=&quot;http://ja.doukaku.org/lang/&quot;&gt;doukaku&lt;/a&gt; (coding challenges) and &lt;a href=&quot;http://amachang.art-code.org/pr/&quot;&gt;S6&lt;/a&gt; (a presentation framework). You can seem a summary of Akky's presentation &lt;a href=&quot;http://asiajin.com/blog/2008/05/16/tokyo2point0-event-cybozu-labs-and-phishing-web-20-security/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Its a bit different - but basically the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next presenter was &lt;a href=&quot;http://mellowtone.co.jp/&quot;&gt;ARAI Shunichi&lt;/a&gt;. He was working in Ruby doing some neat things related to a startup in stealth mode. He showed us a Ruby framework he had written called &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/egalite/&quot;&gt;Egalite&lt;/a&gt; which is supposed to be even simpler than rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was awesome to hang out with technologists who were doing neat things and interested in talking about their projects. I hope i get another chance to go to an AA-Camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple days later, I met up with Tsutomu Kodama. He works for &lt;a href=&quot;http://japan-hopper.com&quot;&gt;Japan Hopper&lt;/a&gt;, a site for backpackers and travelers in japan. it looks to be a google maps wiki mashup allow for people to annotate places and add cool traveler info. Neat. He took us to the small streets behind Omotesando and Harajuku. I was able to find some awesome shoes, check out amazing eyeglasses and eat at a really neat small resturant. I think that any technology person who is in Tokyo and wants to see neat things should attempt to contact Kodama. He is full of awesome places and good tips. He is also quite similar to myself (in a eeire way) and we got along quite well. A great afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its exciting to have friends in Japan that are technologists. Now i know that next time i am there i will have the opportunity to network more and meet others.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Excla.im - a replacement jabber bot</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/07/13/exclaim-a-replacement-jabber-bot.html"/>
   <updated>2008-07-13T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/07/13/exclaim-a-replacement-jabber-bot</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I use twitter quite a bit. I like to post to twitter in the most unobtrusive way possible. I don't like to interupt my workflow to post a quick thought or update. When they used to have their Jabber bot running - it was easy for me to just type in my update and get on with my gmail session or work. I didn't have to load a page that was often down, or use some other tool. I was bummed when the jabber bot went away. I needed it back to keep up with my use case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got tired of waiting, so i made &lt;a href=&quot;http://excla.im&quot;&gt;Excla.im&lt;/a&gt;. It is a simple &lt;a href=&quot;http://appengine.google.com/&quot;&gt;App Engine&lt;/a&gt; hosted application that allows a person to very simply update their twitter status from any jabber account. It is not very feature full, doesn't update all the other sites and doesn't do much else besides just interact with the twitter API. It is very simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technology behind it is just as simple. The GAE app is written in python and uses the &lt;a href=&quot;http://google-app-engine-django.googlecode.com/&quot;&gt;django helper&lt;/a&gt;. It is super simple and is basically a storage container for account info. It was a breeze to develop and fun to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Jabber bot was a bit more complicated. I ended up using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/sleekxmpp/&quot;&gt;sleekxmpp library&lt;/a&gt; to do all the XMPP heavy lifting. It is an awesome library. Makes all the hard stuff easy. I then used &lt;a href=&quot;http://hathawaymix.org/&quot;&gt;Shane Hathaway's&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://hathawaymix.org/Software/Sketches/daemon.py&quot;&gt;daemon.py&lt;/a&gt; to help daemonize the bot (btw thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://anders.conbere.org/&quot;&gt;Anders&lt;/a&gt; for talking me through the dirtiness of daemonizing). To hook into twitter I used the &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/python-twitter/&quot;&gt;python twitter&lt;/a&gt; library. It is featureful and super easy to use. It also supports in newer versions (post &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/p/python-twitter/source/browse/trunk/twitter.py?r=112&quot;&gt;r112&lt;/a&gt;) setting the source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was then able to wrap this all up in a fancy little bot that on receiving a message, grabs encrypted credentials from the GAE app, sends the message to twitter's api and then chills out. Pretty sweet. Currently all the heavy lifting is on the bot side, instead of on the webapp side - but i may change that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At some point, I would like to be able to grab a users twitter friends updates and push them to their jabber ids. However - I have yet to figure out a nice and clean way to get the updates without having them seem batched. I have some ideas and a couple things fleshed out - but i don't want to totally replicate twitter just to get my friends updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am toying with putting the bot up on google code since it is pretty simple and could easily be hooked into almost any webapp. I think that the idea of a simple (simpler than sleekbot) webapp integrated jabber bot would have been helpful in writing this - and i imagine that people looking to do a similar thing may have use for my hacked together code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple take aways from doing this project. First off - python is fun. Second - working with a designer makes things look a LOT better. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aaronsalmon.com/&quot;&gt;Aaron Salmon&lt;/a&gt; took some time to make excla.im look MUCH better than it did. Check out his stuff and hire him.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The free new N95 vs the old iPhone</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/06/09/the-free-new-n95-vs-the-old-iphone.html"/>
   <updated>2008-06-09T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/06/09/the-free-new-n95-vs-the-old-iphone</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright&quot; style=&quot;float: right;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.cellphonebeat.com/images/n95-iphone_48.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;251&quot; height=&quot;201&quot; /&gt;It all started years ago when i got a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nokia_6600&quot;&gt;Nokia 6600&lt;/a&gt;. It was a dope phone and it really raised the bar for me in regards to my expectations for a smart phone. It was one of the first &quot;good&quot; symbian devices. In regards to today's standards - it isn't that great. But back then it rocked the house. I remember telling my friends &quot;OMG. check it out. you can take movies!&quot; and running around making movies. After the 6600, I picked up a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nokia_7610&quot;&gt;Nokia 7610&lt;/a&gt;. This device was basically the same, although a bunch faster and a bundle of better looks. it was quite stylish. Then came the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/N70&quot;&gt;N70&lt;/a&gt;. Then came the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nokia_E61&quot;&gt;E61&lt;/a&gt;. Then the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nokia_E50&quot;&gt;E50&lt;/a&gt;. Then the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/N73&quot;&gt;N73&lt;/a&gt;. And then the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nokia_E61#E61i_2&quot;&gt;E61i&lt;/a&gt;. Each iteration was much much better and faster. It was a fun to go through those. You could have called me a Nokia fan boy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPhone&quot;&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt;. It basically broke my conception of how smart phones should work. The full browser, the full email client, and simple applications made me realize that i would rather have a good phone that does a lot of stuff well - than a good platform that does a lot of stuff mediocre. It took a minute for me to realize that (so much that I gave my first iPhone to Hiromi, thinking that I didn't like it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awhile back, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.womworld.com/&quot;&gt;Nokia WOM&lt;/a&gt; emailed me and asked if i wanted to test drive a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/N95&quot;&gt;N95 8gb&lt;/a&gt; for free. I of course accepted the challenge. There was no catch, requirements, etc. They wanted me to blog about it and let people know what i thought - but they certainly didn't require this. It also wasn't mine forever, just a test drive. I was stoked. This is the device that dreams were made of. It was all that was good in the world. It had real GPS, ran symbian, had decent media, ngage, etc, etc, etc. It was basically the culmination of all i thought i needed in a mobile device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wondered how it would compare to the iphone i had been using for almost a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It didn't. I used it for an hour and couldn't deal with it. it was hard to use. hard to make calls. hard to take pictures. hard to listen to music. hard to figure out where I was with GPS (honestly, that was the clencher. All I wanted was to update a webpage with my location using GPS. I got it going by hacking my iphone easier than using the N95). It made me remember why I liked the iphone. It made me bummed that the &quot;best&quot; phone in the world kinda sucked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I gave the phone to my buddy &lt;a href=&quot;http://craigshimala.com&quot;&gt;Craig&lt;/a&gt; at work. He loves it. It was a great upgrade to his POS dying Sony Ericsson. He planned to use it until the new iPhone comes out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess Nokia is going to have to rethink how their phones work. I was their super fan. I read all the blogs, proselytized their phones, hung out with their engineers, and loved their products. However, I am unwilling to give up the experience that I have with the iPhone. The ease of use, the full browser, the big screen and the platform that isn't insane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am excited to see where this innovation (or lack there of) takes us. I imagine that Nokia will bounce back, but certainly not any pre-iPhone devices. Stay tuned for sure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am really thankful for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.womworld.com/&quot;&gt;Nokia&lt;/a&gt; giving me this experience. Even though it wasn't the phone for me, it was fun to play with and think about why it wasn't my thing. It is still a dope phone even if it isn't beating the iPhone.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>YES WE CAN. Obama apparently wins the democratic nomination</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/06/04/yes-we-can-obama-apparently-wins-the-democratic-nomination.html"/>
   <updated>2008-06-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/06/04/yes-we-can-obama-apparently-wins-the-democratic-nomination</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3095/2550266230_7a54e00363_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.barackobama.com&quot;&gt;Barack Obama&lt;/a&gt; seems to have won the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.abcnews.go.com/Politics/Vote2008/story?id=4987177&amp;amp;page=1&quot;&gt;democratic nomination&lt;/a&gt;. After all the time and work we all put into his campaign, I am VERY happy to hear this news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am more happy that Hilary Clinton didn't win. She was really hurting my insides me with all the negative campaigning. I did not like how attacky she got in the end. I hope that she is done being annoying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now is the time to start supporting the Barack Obama, and the democratic party to defeat John McCain in November. Electing McCain is basically saying that you love President Bush and really want to fuck up the United States. I am not a fan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of having Obama be the democratic nominee is that he invokes hope in people, not fear. I am tired of fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go donate money now.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Speaking at TechCocktail conference on thursday</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/05/28/speaking-at-techcocktail-conference-on-thursday.html"/>
   <updated>2008-05-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/05/28/speaking-at-techcocktail-conference-on-thursday</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright&quot; style=&quot;float: right;&quot; src=&quot;http://techcocktail.com/home/wp-content/themes/revolution-20/images/logo.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;260&quot; height=&quot;158&quot; /&gt;On Thursday the 29th, the TechCocktail Conference is happening at Layola. You should go, and while you are there, you should come check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://morefishthanman.com&quot;&gt;Scottv&lt;/a&gt; and my talk on technology agnosticism. It should be delightful. For those of you that know me - the time slot is hilarious: 9:30 in the morning. Wth. I rarely have an interesting happening that early in the morning. I am usually sleeping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://techcocktail.com/home/tech-cocktail-conference/&quot;&gt;Here is some generic info&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcocktail.com/home/tech-cocktail-conference/speakers/#HARPERREED&quot;&gt;This is my bio&lt;/a&gt;. We are finalizing our presentation (i.e. writing it) and are attempting to figure out how to beat our &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.google.com/Presentation?id=dd3wvxq5_43gq3g4x&quot;&gt;last presentations&lt;/a&gt;. I will post slides later. I promise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.google.com/Presentation?id=df4n6gb3_98j4bs2mfk&quot;&gt;here are the slides from our presentation&lt;/a&gt;. It seemed to go pretty well. It was really fun to participate and speak. I have also placed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/nata2&quot;&gt;all my presentations on slideshare&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Location hacking. Or how I am addicted to knowing where I am</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/05/28/location-hacking-or-how-i-am-addicted-to-knowing-where-i-am.html"/>
   <updated>2008-05-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/05/28/location-hacking-or-how-i-am-addicted-to-knowing-where-i-am</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright&quot; style=&quot;float: right;&quot; src=&quot;http://maps.google.com/staticmap?markers=41.6424713135,-87.9443130493,blue&amp;amp;center=41.6424713135,-87.9443130493&amp;amp;zoom=6&amp;amp;size=200x200&amp;amp;key=ABQIAAAAIFubrKPMu40p2O60-CINYhQC7HvwkBQIUfVW0Yi6qdDdLqLJJhT3qtFTsqKFKqtNsK7OiUle268hSw&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;The last few weeks have been a whirl wind of travel, emergencies and fun events. All of it has made my life a mess in regards to plans, knowing whats up and keeping track of where i am supposed to go and when. Out of necessity, I decided it might be fun to track where I have been and where I am going. To handle this I use various sites like &lt;a href=&quot;http://dopplr.com/&quot;&gt;Dopplr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tripit.com/&quot;&gt;TripIt&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://fireeagle.com/&quot;&gt;fireeagle&lt;/a&gt; to keep track of my travels. Dopplr is my favorite, however I use TripIt to overall manage my travels and then push it into Dopplr and fireeagle - so my friends can be alerted as to where I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After melding all these things together - i decided it would be neat to have the info on my homepage. So, i created this &quot;mashup&quot; to keep track of everything. It was my first foray into being a consumer of oauth (myself, programatically) and i really like it. I am for sure going to use this for the threadless API when it launches (thanks friends!). Dopplr's API is a pain in the ass (there is about 1 page of API documentation), but i finally figured it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of the sites melded together - i was able to get my current location (fireeagle),  and my future and past travels (dopplr). The info for both of these sites is provided in part by dopplr and tripit. Tripit feeding dopplr which feeds fireeagle. I feed tripit with emails. It has been hungry lately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seeing all this info together on my home page made me think of &lt;a href=&quot;http://labs.harahap.org/stalkilya.php&quot;&gt;my friends page&lt;/a&gt; where he tracks exactly where he is at all times. its kinda freaky and pretty invasive. But i wanted to know if i could build it. And i figured that building the gps &quot;puck&quot; as Ilya calls it would be a good experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since i have an iphone instead of a phone with true GPS, I used an &lt;a href=&quot;http://ericasadun.com/?p=188&quot;&gt;app made by Erica Sadun&lt;/a&gt; (an awesome apple hacker) that queries the wifi APs and cell towers that the iphone uses to handle its pseudo GPS. With this app I am able to grab my location and post it to a script i made to track everything. From the script I am able to handle posting to fireeagle or twitter or whatever. A lot of the &lt;a title=&quot;this is an awesome writeup btw&quot; href=&quot;http://soylentfoo.jnewland.com/&quot;&gt;writeups&lt;/a&gt; of this sort of thing have the iphone handle the posting to fireeagle or twitter, however that doesn't really make sense to me - since having less http calls on the actual device seems to be a better plan for battery dominance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can check out my current-ish location &lt;a href=&quot;http://harperreed.org/where/now&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The theme for this spring is travel</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/05/03/th-e-theme-for-this-spring-is-travel.html"/>
   <updated>2008-05-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/05/03/th-e-theme-for-this-spring-is-travel</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Man. It has been a long time since I really felt like blogging. Blogging is weird sometimes. I finds myself being VERY busy and not having the time nor energy to blog thoroughly, so i end up forfeiting an entry, when i could have easily whipped up a couple paragraphs describing whats going on. I instead find myself concentrating on twitter or something else. Its pretty cool - but not as important as my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last couple months and the next couple months are all about travel. Its insane. It reminds me how much i love traveling, but how much I HATE flying. I used to love flying, but recently it has only been horrible experiences. I don't know why it is so horrible, but for some reason - I have had NOTHING but bad experiences. It makes me not want to fly any longer. I need to work on just appearing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After speaking at the U of A in Tucson, I went on to fly to San Antonio to hang out with Rackspace for a week. It was pretty awesome. We had &lt;a href=&quot;http://hideyourarms.com/2008/03/21/threadless-went-down-so-you-get-a-coupon/&quot;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stacksafe.com/blog/2008/04/02/case-studies-for-the-cost-of-downtime/&quot;&gt;problems&lt;/a&gt; we needed to ferret out and Rackspace was very facilitative. I have always found it so much easier to work with people once you have met them and hung out. Then - the repertoire is much more than just the mysterious phone voice that tells you things. It was awesome to meet our team, flesh out our migrations and other various upcoming projects. San Antonio is a very strange place. I am not sure what i think of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After San Antonio, most of the Threadless engineering team flew to Santa Clara for the 2008 MySQL Conference. As always, the conference was great. I had a nice time and was able to see a lot of my friends and talk shit about technology and how to name hosting companies (It's Mosso like MOSS. Not like mow). A couple of highlights from the conference were meeting and hanging out with &lt;a href=&quot;http://romeda.org/&quot;&gt;Blaine Cook&lt;/a&gt;; getting my &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/natatwo/2460459966/&quot;&gt;picture taken by Julian Cash&lt;/a&gt;; and having dinner with various engineers from MySQL, Digg, Mosso and Rackspace. The conference (like all conferences i think) was best experienced through the people who were there, not the actual sessions (although there were some cool ones - memcached, IMVU, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately after landing in chicago from the bay, we flew to NYC for a R&amp;amp;D conference with Insight Venture Partners (investors in skinnyCorp/Threadless). The conference was interesting. A lot of the companies that attended with us were experiencing very different growth that we are - so a lot of the sessions were not targeted towards small development teams. It seemed that they were attempted to work how we work, but through philosophies like scrumm and agile methodologies. Interesting to talk about, but it doesn't really fit us. We were, however, able to go to some excellent places to eat. On Monday, we went to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.employeesonlynyc.com/&quot;&gt;Employees Only&lt;/a&gt;. And then we went to the pretentious &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sohohouseny.com/launch.html#9***1***1&quot;&gt;SoHo house.&lt;/a&gt; I found Employees Only to be awesome. It had excellent food and quite a drink menu. We also were able to have a really great time there. It wasn't too pretentious and the people around us didn't mind us having fun. The SoHo House had mediocre food and a weird vibe. My NY friends mentioned something about it being frequented by &lt;a href=&quot;http://gawker.com/news/hit-piece/principal-hells-the-rough-guide-to-soho-house-203290.php&quot;&gt;bankers&lt;/a&gt; - but it seemed more hip than that, but that may have contributed to the weird atmosphere. Regardless of the food and atmosphere, the view was great. After dinner, we ended up at &lt;a href=&quot;http://newyork.citysearch.com/profile/44527657/new_york_ny/205_bar.html&quot;&gt;205&lt;/a&gt; for a LOT of drinks and entertaining shit talking. Great times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That brings us to the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I am going to be going to San Antonio again to finalize some of our discussions with our team. Then Colorado for &lt;a href=&quot;http://atkinx.com&quot;&gt;Atkins&lt;/a&gt; wedding, and finally to &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Yamanashi_Prefecture&quot;&gt;Yamanashi&lt;/a&gt; for Hiromi's grandfathers final funeral (and to hang out in Japan). A lot of traveling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this flux of traveling, I have become a bit obsessed with tracking it in interesting ways. For instance, i have been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://Tripit.com&quot;&gt;Tripit.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dopplr.com/traveller/natatwo&quot;&gt;dopplr.com&lt;/a&gt; to track various aspects of my trips. I have tripit.com hooked into dopplr.com so that I don't actually have to do any work. Just email my plans to tripit and BAM - dopplr is updated. pretty cool.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Speaking at the University of Arizona</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/04/05/speaking-at-the-university-of-arizona.html"/>
   <updated>2008-04-05T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/04/05/speaking-at-the-university-of-arizona</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a title=&quot;My name tag + our presentation by nata2, on Flickr&quot; href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/natatwo/2372161865/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2010/2372161865_3f20e8892f_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My name tag + our presentation&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; align=&quot;right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The other weekend, &lt;a href=&quot;http://charlesfesta.com/&quot;&gt;Charlie&lt;/a&gt; and I, flew to the University of Arizona to speak at their &lt;a href=&quot;http://marketing.eller.arizona.edu/thinkingforward/conference.aspx&quot;&gt;Thinking Forward Leadership and Innovation in Marketing Conference&lt;/a&gt;. It was a cool experience. The people who were involved with the Conference are rather intelligent and they really blew my mind in regards to their thoughts on Threadless/social media/Internet communities. They have words that I have never used that they use to describe the things I do every day. Weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trip was hilarious from the get go. On a Thursday, we flew into Phoenix via SouthWest. That airline is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search?q=southwest+sucks&quot;&gt;clusterfuck&lt;/a&gt;. I am not a fan. However, it is much better when we have &quot;Business Class&quot; tickets - which apparently means we get a drink ticket to dull the pain, and get to board a bit earlier than the others. It was a mess of annoying drunk middle aged women on a group trip, children and indignant and entitled business men who thought they were all that. We owned them all. Once we landed, we rented a &lt;a href=&quot;http://flickr.com/photos/natatwo/2372164187/&quot;&gt;very stupid car&lt;/a&gt;, and then drove the neat/boring drive to Tucson. Once we got to Tucson, we wrote our presentation (luckily &lt;a href=&quot;http://callmejeffrey.com&quot;&gt;Jeffrey&lt;/a&gt; has spent countless hours creating legitimate slides for us slackers to pilfer) and got on our way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had some awesome Mexican Food. Went to a couple hilarious bars, met some cool people, and ended up at a lesbian bar. It was pretty different than our times in chicago. ;) The night life in Tucson, near the college, is full of college kids. Weird. Being around so many young people was invigorating. And annoying. haha. GOD I am so old. OMG.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we went to the event and spoke. It went over well. We got some good feedback. Like: don't swear as much, don't put up Obama 2008 slides and practice before we actually do it. I thought that was decent feedback. I think if we did it again the only thing I wouldn't change is the Obama slide, and it seem that was the most offensive. Apparently, you are not supposed to be political at all on a college campus. I wonder when this happened? It certainly wasn't like this when I was in college. Maybe at a &quot;conservative&quot; business school, things are different. Regardless, if I were to speak there again - and the political climate is the same as it is now, I would put the same slide up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other people we spoke with were amazing. Particularly Robert V. Kozinets. This dude is awesome. He has written extensively about &lt;a href=&quot;http://kozinets.net/archives/97&quot;&gt;tribes on the internets&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burningman.com/whatisburningman/2003/03_news_sum4.html&quot;&gt;burning man&lt;/a&gt;. I imagine that you have read about him before (even if you didn't notice). We ended up hanging out with him quite a bit. Another person who uses words I have never heard to describe things that we do everyday. I am particularly interested in his work on Burning Man. I guess I will have to read it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all the festivities of the event were over, we chilled on the streets of Tucson, and eventually met up some of the staff of the Eller College of Management for dinner. The dinner was great, but even more great was meeting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.drsidneyjlevy.com/&quot;&gt;Sidney Levy&lt;/a&gt;. Sidney is apparently one of the people who &lt;a href=&quot;http://books.google.com/books?hl=en&amp;amp;id=IB95hkJczk4C&amp;amp;dq=sidney+levy&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;ots=fRR2Nkl7id&amp;amp;sig=7XQtrnSG0b-MaKDq1g4xXxbBDsQ#PPP1,M1&quot;&gt;developed the world of brand marketing&lt;/a&gt;. He was billed as the father of symbolic marketing. This is serious business. However, he was very much not serious business. He was awesome. Charlie and I hung out with him for about an hour, just talking about life, love and all things that occur between. Sidney was quite funny and had a lot to tell us. I am going to attempt to help him get his gullibility project going. Excitement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking is pretty awesome. I learned a lot from talking to the people around us. It was awesome to hang out with young people who are excited about something that I am not excited about. Inspiring and hope giving. I hope that Charlie and I get to do it again. Hopefully in Hawaii, or maybe Guam, or possibly some other paradisiacal place.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Social XMPP</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/03/25/social-xmpp.html"/>
   <updated>2008-03-25T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/03/25/social-xmpp</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last week my friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://mark.atwood.name&quot;&gt;Mark&lt;/a&gt; pinged me and mentioned that I should get together with a friend of his who was in town for PYCON. I am always into meeting new people so I had dinner with &lt;a href=&quot;http://dorseys.org/&quot;&gt;Brian Dorsey&lt;/a&gt;. It was awesome. I was able to rant and rave about all my ideas, interests and whatnot with new and possibly interested. Brian immediately suggested that he introduce me to a friend of his who he thought I would enjoy talking to. So I was introduced to &lt;a href=&quot;http://anders.conbere.org/journal/&quot;&gt;Anders Conbere&lt;/a&gt;. The reason Brian thought we should meet was that we both incessantly talk about XMPP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anders and I talked for a couple hours Friday, and found that we had a lot of similar ideas and thoughts about XMPP and its place in the world of social software, communities and data. Anders explained that we weren't the only crazies who thought that XMPP should be used for more than instant messaging. He mentioned that &lt;a href=&quot;http://stpeter.im/&quot;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://romeda.org/&quot;&gt;cool&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hackdiary.com/&quot;&gt;kids&lt;/a&gt; were also looking into the relationship of XMPP and social software. As Anders was dashing out the door to his flight, we decided that we needed to create or at least foster the growth of a mailing list to collect people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier today, Anders introduced me to &lt;a href=&quot;http://stpeter.im/&quot;&gt;Peter Saint-Andre&lt;/a&gt; who is the Executive Director of the XMPP Standards Foundation. We chatted a bit and then came to the conclusion that there needed to be a place for people to talk about their ideas, uses, experiences and what not. And thus &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:social@xmpp.org&quot;&gt;social@xmpp.org&lt;/a&gt; was &lt;a href=&quot;https://stpeter.im/?p=2177&quot;&gt;born as the go to mailing list to discuss these topics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a lot of ideas and hopefully with the help of this group, I can flush them out and really tackle them. I am pretty excited about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Those parties were awesome!</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/03/11/those-parties-were-awesome.html"/>
   <updated>2008-03-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/03/11/those-parties-were-awesome</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am finally recovered from my flash travel/party tour. Being shuttled around the country going to parties is a rough life - let me tell you. It was awesome. I met some great people and saw some really cool stuff. It was really cool how much overlap occurred between the boulder crowd and SXSW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Startup people are fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to run down the events and how they turned out. The first was boulder. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keepboulderweird.org/&quot;&gt;Boulder is a weird place&lt;/a&gt;. Seriously. It is strange. The boulder event was at this bar called the Foundry. I am guessing that if it wasn't packed to the gills with tech people from the front range, I would never go there. It was a pretty hilarious venue, however the tech people really filled it out. So it turned out to be a great choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In boulder there were a lot of cool startups presenting. The one that really caught my eye was &lt;a href=&quot;http://socialthing.com&quot;&gt;Socialthing&lt;/a&gt;. These guys are sweet. They are doing a very simple and elegant solution for the crowded social aggregation space. Although I really like the community features of their direct competitor &lt;a href=&quot;http://friendfeed.com&quot;&gt;FriendFeed&lt;/a&gt;, I like the design and interface of socialthing alot. It is great - and they are sweet guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a fair number of other startups, but unless they have real words in their names - i won't link them. Just kidding, but seriously - there were a fair number of people with startups that plain didn't have the best names. It is a bummer. Especially because the people were so nice and their ideas/technology seemed solid. It is &lt;a href=&quot;http://deliberately-different.blogspot.com/2006/02/how-they-named-companies.html&quot;&gt;hard to&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.salon.com/media/col/shal/1999/11/30/naming/print.html&quot;&gt;name a&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.guykawasaki.com/2006/02/the_name_game.html&quot;&gt;company&lt;/a&gt;. Anyway - some of the not so awesomely named but awesome technology and problem solution startups in boulder are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://Lijit.com&quot;&gt;Lijit.com&lt;/a&gt; - doing search for your blog. kinda like google site search, but with your social graph built in. Really cool stuff.

&lt;a href=&quot;http://Villij.com&quot;&gt;Villij.com&lt;/a&gt; - not my favorite name. The guys are cool and they have some cool ideas about recommendations in the social graph space.&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I also met a really awesome &quot;startup enabler&quot; named &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeremytanner.com/&quot;&gt;Jeremy Tanner&lt;/a&gt;. He seems to do what I do at Threadless for various startups in the Colorado scene. Jeremy moved from Detroit to Colorado - so he had a lot of input on how it was going from city to smaller city. He had great things to say about being able to jump on his motorcycle and head to the canyons for an awesome lunch time experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After this event, I crashed at my hotel. Spent some time with my parents and was off to SXSW for ONE day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With much insanity, I finally made it to Austin and barely made it to the People Powered Powwow. It was awesome. Hearing the experiences of &lt;a href=&quot;http://etsy.com&quot;&gt;Etsy&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timbuk2.com/tb2/products/bagbuilder&quot;&gt;Timbuk2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://moo.com/&quot;&gt;Moo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jpgmag.com/&quot;&gt;JPG&lt;/a&gt; and all the other awesome companies was quite inspiring. It was also awesome to meet the people who are behind all these awesome brands. It was like a secret people powered club where we all tell our people powering secrets. A really powerful meetup. I am glad that &lt;a href=&quot;http://richardmoross.com/&quot;&gt;Richard&lt;/a&gt; (from moo) set it up. it alone was worth the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the companies that were there that I really liked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://styleshake.com/user/&quot;&gt;Styleshake&lt;/a&gt; - I was surprised by this one. Styleshake is a neat community that helps facilitate custom dresses. Another thing I would have never guessed would be made into a crowd sourcing enterprise - but it works. And it seems to work well. The dresses are cool and the variations are impressive. If I was a svelte young woman I would certainly check this out.

&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burdastyle.com/&quot;&gt;BurdaStyle&lt;/a&gt; - I thought this was the coolest idea i had heard in awhile. Open source sewing patterns. Taking various patterns and releasing the designs to the community to create and manipulate. Helping to foster the crafting, sewing world as well as create awesome clothes.&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;After the mini conference, I was fortunate enough to have dinner with the JPG people and  Wilson Minor (&lt;a href=&quot;http://everyblock.com&quot;&gt;EveryBlock&lt;/a&gt;). We ate at some nice Mexican food place. It was good, better than Chicago Mexican food. Then I made my way to the soon to be &lt;a href=&quot;http://upcoming.yahoo.com/event/430139/&quot;&gt;bumping party&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The party was fun. There were a lot of people. Floss seemed to be well accepted and it was awesome to meet &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kidkameleon.com/&quot;&gt;kid kameleon&lt;/a&gt;. Around this time I had the awesomeness to bump into a dude from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threadbanger.com/&quot;&gt;Threadbangers&lt;/a&gt;. he was able to capture my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.threadbanger.com/episode/SXSW_20080310&quot;&gt;natural retardedness for an episode of threadbangers&lt;/a&gt;. haha. Whew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my debut in amazing, I was able to take a minute and meet up with some friends. It is fun to hang out with Chicago friends when not in Chicago. I met up with &lt;a href=&quot;http://jacobdehart.com&quot;&gt;Jacob DeHart&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://bloxes.com/&quot;&gt;Aza Raskin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.srobbin.com/&quot;&gt;Scott Robbin&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.humanized.com/about/&quot;&gt;Andrew Wilson&lt;/a&gt;. Another person I was thrilled to meet up with is &lt;a href=&quot;http://mediadiet.net/&quot;&gt;Heath Row&lt;/a&gt;. Heath has always been a favorite person of mine and it is great (and rare) to hang out in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the party died down - we all went to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://PureVolume.com&quot;&gt;Pure Volume&lt;/a&gt; ranch for the Social Thing party and my trip came full circle. I was able to meet up with the Lijit, Villij and Socialthing guys. After rocking out there for a couple hours i decided to head home, sleep and finally attempt to make my way back to Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I barely made it. ;)&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>TechCocktail Boulder and SXSW! Come see me!</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/03/05/traveling-to-parties.html"/>
   <updated>2008-03-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/03/05/traveling-to-parties</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I will be in Colorado tomorrow for &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcocktail.com/home/2008/02/07/tech-cocktail-boulder-1/&quot;&gt;Tech Cocktail Boulder&lt;/a&gt;. It will be awesome to be a part of this event in Boulder. I will be officially representing &lt;a href=&quot;http://skinnycorp.com&quot;&gt;skinnyCorp&lt;/a&gt; - so come get some swag and hang out! For those that have never been to a Tech Cocktail, it is a meet up style event mixing &quot;cocktails&quot; and technology. It offers a great opportunity to meet some of your local technologist, entrepreneurs and other awesome people in the boulder community. It seems that Boulder has a rich startup community being fostered by some &lt;a href=&quot;http://coloradostartups.com/&quot;&gt;cool&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.feld.com/blog/&quot;&gt;guys&lt;/a&gt; - so it should be interesting to see what happens with Tech Cocktail. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Then on Sunday I will be at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://upcoming.yahoo.com/event/430139/&quot;&gt;SxSWi Party by Moo, Etsy, Timbuk2 and Threadless&lt;/a&gt;. Its going to be pretty sweet. Come hang out and drink free beer. According to the upcoming attendee listing, it is going to be packed - so come early. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;If anyone would like to meet up (i.e. boulder tech people), feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;http://harperreed.org/contact&quot;&gt;send me an email&lt;/a&gt; or hit me up on a chat machine. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I will see you guys there!&lt;/p&gt;

</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>OLPC Chicago Jabber Server</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/03/02/olpc-chicago-jabber-server.html"/>
   <updated>2008-03-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/03/02/olpc-chicago-jabber-server</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I spent a minute setting up a &lt;a href=&quot;http://lists.laptop.org/pipermail/olpc-chicago/2008-March/000136.html&quot;&gt;Ejabberd Server&lt;/a&gt; for the OLPC Chicago group. This will allow all of us OLPC XO hackers to be on the same &quot;mesh.&quot; To get started using the jabber server with your XO follow these simple steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Boot the XO&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Get connected to the internet&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Open a terminal (activity or ctrl-alt-f1)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;in the shell, type: su -&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;then type: &lt;i&gt;sugar-control-panel -s jabber jabber.olpchacks.org&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;then press ctrl-alt-erase to restart sugar/X&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Once this is done, you should start to see other Chicago XOs. You will know you are successful if you see me (Harper) in the community view. Please &lt;a href=&quot;http://harperreed.org/contact&quot;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt; if you are able to get on, or if you are having trouble.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting the server going was pretty simple. I was able to jump right in thanks to this &lt;a href=&quot;http://morgancollett.wordpress.com/2008/02/27/olpc-community-jabber-servers-ejabberd-200-from-source/&quot;&gt;awesome write up&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&quot;http://morgancollett.wordpress.com/about/&quot;&gt;Morgan Collett&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.collabora.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Collabora&lt;/a&gt;. The install goes like this: you get your debian install primed, download the source, patch the source, compile the source, install the compiled binaries, edit the config, start the server and edit the server roster config. Then BAM you have a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ejabberd.im/&quot;&gt;ejabberd server&lt;/a&gt; rocking and ready to go with your XO. The only caveat i ran into was that the config file from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Ejabberd_Configuration&quot;&gt;ejabberd wiki page&lt;/a&gt; details using IPV6 because eventually all the laptops will be using IPV6 to get around. However, the server i used was balking at this - and kept crashing ejabberd with the MOST verbose errors ever (I.E. no error). When i finally figured out what the problem was, it was smooth sailing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing to note - ejabberd is seriously business. &lt;a href=&quot;http://erlang.org/&quot;&gt;Erlang&lt;/a&gt; is interesting to work with. I was lost for about 2 hours before I gave up trying to understand what was going on and just dived in. Then it didn't make sense, but was working and I was happy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is really neat how the XO uses jabber to group people together. I really think that jabber is the future and seeing something use XMPP so elegantly is quite inspiring. I found one of the coolest parts of the implementation is how the rosters are forced to see everyone online - which i imagine is what powers the neighborhood view on the XO. This makes me wonder if this could be tweaked to create a more interactive or social networking aspect to the XO neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I would like to know about is how the XO uses the Multi User Chat features of the jabber server. I am not sure if the &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.laptop.org/go/Chat&quot;&gt;Chat Activity&lt;/a&gt; uses MUC to work, but it would be cool if you could chat with XO users with a regular user account on the jabber server by joining a specific room. I will have to research that.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Awesome hosting options</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/03/02/awesome-hosting-options.html"/>
   <updated>2008-03-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/03/02/awesome-hosting-options</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I spend WAY WAY too much time trying to figure out where and how to host my websites. I guess you could it a hobby. A really horrible and expensive hobby. It isn't a great way to meet friends, enjoy life or honestly save money. However - it prepares me for the awesome ability to bitch about hosting and to write this blog entry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks ago, Mosso changed some stuff and got my buddy &lt;a href=&quot;http://broox.com&quot;&gt;Derek&lt;/a&gt; and I got to talking about hosting options if Mosso doesn't pan out. I decided that since I have this perverse hobby, I should document my journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So here is my list of hosting providers I recommend and enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mosso.com&quot;&gt;Mosso&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;: This is currently my friends blog and generic client hosting favorite. It is easy to use, has amazing service and hilarious growing pains. I have been using them for about a year - and have been VERY happy with pretty much everything. They currently have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2008/02/29/the-mosso-cloud-how-requests-are-not-a-good-metric/&quot;&gt;some crazy billing issues&lt;/a&gt; to work out - but when they figure that out, I would certainly recommend using them.  One thing to keep in mind: if you have clients, you can't do any better than Mosso - they can white label EVERYTHING (including phone support). It is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mediatemple.net/&quot;&gt;MediaTemple&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;: These guys are cool. Seriously. I didn't really like MediaTemple until I hung out with the dudes. They are doing cool stuff with virtualization and easy scaling. For instance, you could get one of their horribly named &lt;i&gt;(dv) servers&lt;/i&gt; for around 50 bucks a month and then if you ever have a problem with the resources or &quot;scaling&quot;&quot; abilities with the virtualized server, you can just go ahead and &quot;seamlessly&quot; upgrade to a dedicated box. This is because their dedicated boxes are just virtualized instances as well as the (dv) servers. So upgrading the box is as simple as copying your server image from the shared box to the dedicated box. You don't have to change IPs, copy your content or really any of the stupid shit that makes scaling annoying. Now this is of course in theory (and told to me while i was drunk). I have never actually don't this. BUT - it seems like it should and would work.  (if you can shed some light on this - let me know).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fdcservers.net/&quot;&gt;FDCservers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;: FDC servers is interesting. I can't imagine that they are solid or have good support in times of need. Or that their servers aren't made from ants and cheese. But seriously. They are cheap, support is good and they are FAST. They have some of the cheapest, fastest servers i have ever seen. Its out of control (and fast and cheap (what a good documentary)).  I don't hesitate to use them whenever I need a  fast, cheap server with a FAT pipe. But - I am worried that someday their servers will turn to dust without a warning. But until them - they are my secret dedicated server host.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webfaction.com?affiliate=harper&quot;&gt;Webfaction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;: Webfaction is my new best friend. Seriously. If I wasn't already married to an beautiful, awesome woman, I would marry webfaction. They have blown my mind. You are able to use ANY web technology you want to use. They have decent resource allotments and they are rather inexpensive. Especially considering they are expecting you to use long running processes like Ruby or Python frameworks or apps. Pretty sweet. If you want a host that allows you to host a wordpress blog, experiment with web.py, run a rails app and allow you to rock out with django - all under the same domain root - webfaction is your host. The secret is that its all proxied. So when you set up a rails app, it tells you the port number to run that app on. Then it maps that port number on the localhost of the box to /railsapp on the public IP. I currently host my blog and homepage at webfaction. I trust them more than any of these others (I am furiously knocking on wood you read this).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rackspace.com&quot;&gt;Rackspace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;: Rackspace is obviously not your general needs host. It is probably the best host you can get. But don't just grab a Rackspace server and think your good. You gotta get the intensive support. Its like having a concierge service for your hosting. Its incredible. If you are a small organization, and don't want to have to worry about all the nonsense that goes with managing servers, infrastructures, data centers - then give Rackspace a call. They have really helped us (threadless) grow and scale. They are solid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the hosts I use on a daily basis. All of them i recommend. Obviously you wouldn't use Rackspace to host your not often read blog, and you wouldn't use webfaction to host your $100MM social network. However, all of these options have one thing in common. They all have decent support and they all seem to LOVE what they are doing. I can't deal with vendors who offer products that they themselves wouldn't use. You can't trust those guys. You can trust all these guys (except FDC - with their prices, they have to be doing something tricky. heh. ).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Mosso Cloud: Requests are not a good metric</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/02/29/the-mosso-cloud-how-requests-are-not-a-good-metric.html"/>
   <updated>2008-02-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/02/29/the-mosso-cloud-how-requests-are-not-a-good-metric</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE: &lt;/b&gt;Not a moment after i posted this - i got a mosso mailing that explained an upgrade in the plan. I will leave the original number in because i still think my point is valid and because that is what new Mosso customers will be getting. Their update is just a quick fix to stop us from bitching. It isn't solving the problem.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2007/06/05/hosting-woes-collocation-and-how-mosso-sucks&quot;&gt;blogged about Mosso before&lt;/a&gt;. I have used them practically from their inception (well before they were cool. hah). I have been happy and I have been totally pissed. but for the most part they have done an amazing job of doing shared hosting in the most unsucky way possible. The features and capabilities they offer are hard to beat. They have some quirks and growing pains - but what shared host doesn't. But Mosso is quite different than most shared hosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is really neat about Mosso is that Mosso is just a giant cluster. So your sites are load balanced across many many servers. Its how I imagined cloud or &quot;grid&quot; hosting should be. And it works. and it works well.  You don't have to worry about your small site being sucked of its life by a larger site that sits on the same server. every site is spread over multiple servers - so your site
gets the same priority as a HUGE site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its awesome. and super cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am hosting around 150 sites for 100 bucks a month. With crazy white label options and more features than almost any host. I use it primarily for hosting all my shitty domains and for hosting my friends blogs and sites. I don't host large sites on there, but I do have probably more on Mosso than I should in one account. I never hit any of the resource limits and I was never told to host less. In fact - there are no limits to what you can host as long as you stay within the resource limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, I am not alone in this use case. I imagine that many clients are abusing their cluster the same way I am, with no practical repercussion and no way to limit them without drastically changing their plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am guessing Mosso was looking at their usage and looking at us horrible clients - and figured that they were getting owned. So they decided to set up a new resource metric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How they picked requests, I will never know. But they decided to bill based on requests. So each person gets 3MM requests a month. This is some 1995 shit. I mean - requests is just an annoying &quot;web 2.0 cloud computing market speak&quot; for hits. Everyone knows what a hit is. everyone knows that you can have a shitty site and have a lot of hits. Nobody uses hits as a metric. Except Mosso ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Mosso's new pricing, you get charged for each &quot;hit&quot; to a site that is hosted at Mosso. If you go over your 3MM allotment, you get charged at $0.03 for each 1000 &quot;hits&quot; to your site. seriously. three cents for every 1000 hits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means - if you have a horrible blog that has 50 images on every page load. And you get around 2500 views a day (which is a lot - but not unrealistic). You will use up all your &quot;hits&quot; for that month. But if I don't have all those images, my 2500 view a day blog will not use all the &quot;hits&quot; up. Keep in mind as well that Mosso is a place where you are able to host an unlimited number of sites. So what happens if you have 50 clients, and each client is using around .5MM &quot;hits&quot; a month. You end up paying about ~$750 in overage for your cheap shared hosting. per month. Suddenly Mosso is more expensive than a NICE dedicated box from Server Beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagine that the 5MM &quot;hits&quot; is just a rough number they thought up. I am guessing they are going to change that number. Offer a couple price plans and generally try and make things better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My concern is not in them attempting to make things better, more equal or for them to change the pricing into a more ala cart type of offering. My concern is in the requests metric. It doesn't make sense. There are lot better ways to measure server usage than something that is arbitrary and negatively impacts the people who are building these sites. People who use a premade CMS like drupal or wordpress may incur more charges than people who are using simpler, css based custom sites. People who have sites that are heavy in graphics (graphic designers, ad people, agency people) will all be effected - because they are more worried about how the site looks and how it is presented - not how many &quot;hits&quot; each page view will take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole philosophy of Mosso seems to be for them to take the much needed place of being a simple shared host targeting designers and other internet people who dont want to worry about their hosting and don't want to pay for a dedicated box. Someone who wants to give their client SOLID hosting, but doesn't want to hire a sysadmin. It seems to me that those people are not going to want to start worrying about how many &quot;hits&quot; each page view gets, nor are they going to want educate their clients that the more successful their site gets - the more they have to pay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the &quot;pay for what you use&quot; model is the future. It doesn't make sense for me, with sites that are using 90% of a servers resources to pay the same as someone who is using 10% of a servers resources. However, it should be something that is quantifiable and based on actual server usage. Not something that is relative to how your site is laid out and created.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Google Apps Auth: XMPP and Radius idea</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/02/25/google-apps-auth-xmpp-and-radius-idea.html"/>
   <updated>2008-02-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/02/25/google-apps-auth-xmpp-and-radius-idea</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At work we use &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com/a&quot;&gt;Google Apps&lt;/a&gt; for our enterprise email and calendaring. We use pretty much the entire gamut of tools Google provides us. And for the most part, we love it. It is great to have an easy to use, inexpensive suite of hosted tools that you can use from anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gmail is far better than outlook for our organization and the other tools just help make things go smoothly. We use docs quite a bit for knowledge share and even use it some in the warehouse for quality control and what not. its neat stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, we have been adding various appliances to our organization that can authenticate users based on an &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ldap&quot;&gt;LDAP data store&lt;/a&gt; or a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RADIUS&quot;&gt;Radius server&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started with one of out &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Samba_%28software%29&quot;&gt;file servers&lt;/a&gt;. I wanted to make it so people have their own share for archiving and backing up personal documents. A place that is &quot;protected&quot; by their password. But with 35 employees possibly accessing the file server, it is not efficient to have another ACL system. So ultimately it would be nice to have it use Google Apps as authentication portion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I googled a bunch and forgot that this was a goal. Until this last month when we added an awesome wifi mesh system (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aerohive.com/&quot;&gt;Aerohive&lt;/a&gt; - hit me up if you want hooked up with them, awesome stuff) and we grabbed a MUCH better VPN subsystem (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.juniper.net/products_and_services/ssl_vpn_secure_access/&quot;&gt;Juniper SSLVPN&lt;/a&gt;). Both require user auth to work most securely. Which means that in the best case, both would authenticate to the same ACL system that the file server is authenticating against.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once again, the problem of integrating Google Apps accounts into an LDAP/Radius service was brought to my attention.  It seems like it should be something that is relatively easy to integrate. However, I can't quite grasp the &lt;a href=&quot;http://code.google.com/apis/apps/sso/saml_reference_implementation.html&quot;&gt;SAML offering that the Google Apps API suggests using&lt;/a&gt; for SSO. I couldn't easily figure out if this would be an option for web only authentication, or I could drop it into a &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.freeradius.org/Base_Modules&quot;&gt;freeradius module&lt;/a&gt; (using &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.freeradius.org/Rlm_python&quot;&gt;rlm_python&lt;/a&gt;). It also seems that it is a way to use a radius server to authenticate a local user into their Google Apps account. Not the direction that I want. It seems like this should be possible, but i wasn't able to find any help on the various Google Groups that suggested that it possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got to thinking. If I am going to be hacking away at a python module for freeradius or using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wiggy.net/code/pyrad/&quot;&gt;pyrad&lt;/a&gt; to create a radius server - why couldn't I just have it authenticate against Google Apps jabber server. Basically using &lt;a href=&quot;http://xmpppy.sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;XMPPPY&lt;/a&gt; or whatever to hit talk.google.com and check if a user is authenticating correctly, and if so let them in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The immediate benefit of piggy backing on Google's jabber server is that I would be able to bypass managing user accounts or passwords. They would be managed by the users themselves or by whoever is managing the user accounts. It would be independent of the Radius server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some immediate problems are that all the users would immediately have the same access. If I wanted more granularity of access, I would obviously have to create some ACL system that sat between the XMPP auth and the response to the radius request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am guessing that figuring out if SAML would work would be easiest. I can already tell this is possibly a backwards way of doing it. I just want everything to work well together. And I want to haxor up some python.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Rails and Wired magazine</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/02/23/rails-and-wired-magazine.html"/>
   <updated>2008-02-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/02/23/rails-and-wired-magazine</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Apparently I am in the March Wired magazine. I am not sure exactly what the title of the article or the exact content - but I was interview about my views on the rails community as someone who left the community and moved on to other things. (I think - I haven't seen it - just heard that i was in it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My history with rails is a tumultuous one. I first played with rails pre 1.0 while working with my buddy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.cmu.edu/~acarlson/&quot;&gt;Andy Carlson&lt;/a&gt;.  In a flurry of excited and hilarious programming, I learned ruby and started building web applications in rails. It was a brilliant time. I enjoyed the layout and structure of the applications. I enjoyed the beauty of the Ruby language. Probably most of all, I enjoyed the excitement of learning a new framework and language. One of the things I did - was recreate a couple apps I had written in php. The development time was LOADs faster than the time the same app took to write in PHP. Blew my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suddenly I was a rails advocate. I advocated &lt;a href=&quot;http://sethgodin.typepad.com/&quot;&gt;Seth Godin&lt;/a&gt; use rails for his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.squidoo.com/&quot;&gt;Squidoo&lt;/a&gt; project (he used PHP - I guess I wasn't convincing enough, but he employs a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blogs.squidoo.com/squidblog/?author=2&quot;&gt;great PHP guy&lt;/a&gt;, so no worries). I ended up teaching Rails to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.socialtwister.com/&quot;&gt;Greg Narain&lt;/a&gt; (who now has a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bluewhalelabs.com/&quot;&gt;rails consultant firm&lt;/a&gt;) and I eventually even brought up using rails at &lt;a href=&quot;http://skinnycorp.com&quot;&gt;skinnyCorp&lt;/a&gt;. Right about the time I got turned down to use rails at skinnyCorp (right when I started. hah), I started to notice that any time my rails sites got traffic, they would crash. Then, the upgrade to post 1.0 rails code killed all my rails apps. So I made the sad decision to move a lot of them back to PHP. My servers stopped groaning, I didn't have problems with an upgrade path - but I was bummed because I didn't have a good rake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I was doing PHP full time around this time period, I started trying to move what I learned from rails into our PHP work. I was probably 100% a better coder because of ruby and rails. I was a staunch MVC layout supporter. I was very against procedural PHP in our apps and I fought to the death to try and get all my apps (including skinnyCorps) to have a layout and framework that created a rapid development environment and made sense. (luckily I had the help of &lt;a href=&quot;http://localkinegrinds.com/&quot;&gt;Kanno&lt;/a&gt; to work this out. He totally helped). For inspiration and education I continued to read various rails blogs and started paying attention to other framework projects - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.djangoproject.com/&quot;&gt;django&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cakephp.org/&quot;&gt;cakephp&lt;/a&gt; to name my favorites.  While dabbling in these other communities i started to notice how negative the rails community was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I talked to the wired writer about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate how hard it is to get around in the rails community. From sitting on IRC and mentioning that I use php and then having a flame war erupt, to having to defend various non rails design patterns to every n00b out there who doesn't know who &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.martinfowler.com/&quot;&gt;Martin Fowler&lt;/a&gt; is. It was draining. And to tell you the truth, that is the primary reason that when I left rails - I never came back.  In my experience learning other languages, and other frameworks - I never once heard &quot;omg. you are totally doing it WRONG.&quot; Only while working with the rails community did I ever hear that. and I heard it often. and from the rails leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nata2.org/2007/04/15/rails-woes-the-slow-that-is-keeping-twitter-down/&quot;&gt;I have blogged about this before&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that the rails leaders are killing the rails community. I don't think zed was entirely correct - but I do think he had some great points. But I have been out of it for a minute, so I can't really speak for recent events. But I see what the intraweb sees. And I see a community who is lead by people who are negative, rather mean and not willing to accept criticism at all. But then again, who is able to easily accept criticism and when they are criticized, how should they respond?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea. But for me, I would have liked any reaction that wasn't snarky, soapboxy and that solved the problem - because there are problems and telling people they are wrong is not going to solve them. I think the rails community should probably watch &lt;a href=&quot;http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=-4216011961522818645&quot;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;. They should think before they post. They should abandon their emotions when talking about programming and technology. They should get girlfriends.  Just kidding - all the rails coders I know have hot girlsfriends/wives (which probably exacerbates the annoyance when they are dicks online).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway. Since I live in a glass house and all, I am going to go outside and see if I can't find the new wired. Hopefully I don't look like a dick in it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Obama: yes we can</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/02/04/obama-yes-we-can.html"/>
   <updated>2008-02-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/02/04/obama-yes-we-can</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This weekend I went and volunteered for the Obama Campaign. It was a great experience. I showed up at 12pm and stayed until around 5. I was surrounded by great people who all believed in Obama and his movement. Quite inspiring.
I worked on validating submitted volunteer information. it was tedious work. I went through about 4500 records, sorting and updating. My eyes were done with computers by the time I left.
In the middle of all the data entry and validation, one of the campaign people came into our workroom and showed us the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yeswecansong.com&quot;&gt;will.i.am video &quot;yes we can.&quot;&lt;/a&gt; Amazing. (&lt;a href=&quot;http://youtube.com/watch?v=jjXyqcx-mYY&quot;&gt;youtube link&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/v/2fZHou18Cdk&amp;amp;rel=1&quot; width=&quot;425&quot; height=&quot;355&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; wmode=&quot;transparent&quot;&gt;Watching that with a group of people who are incredibly dedicated to a movement which they believe in is an inspiring event. It made me want to take the week off work and go door to door in some under represented state. The video/song is made by Will.I.Am from black eyed peas and has a cast of quite a few artists who are singing the speech &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://youtube.com/watch?v=Fe751kMBwms&quot;&gt;Obama gave in Nashua, New Hampshire on the night of the New Hampshire primary&lt;/a&gt;. Pretty intense. There is a great &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/garrett-graff/why-yes-we-can-inspires_b_84838.html&quot;&gt;break down of the video by Garrett Graff over at Huffington Post&lt;/a&gt;. Interesting to read about the history of the &quot;Yes We Can&quot; phrase. &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;The whole experience of seeing the campaign inner-workings, working with people who believe in this movement, and just feeling a small amount of membership to this amazing movement was very moving. It was like a spark inside of me. So much hope and excitement. &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;So go and vote. Let's make our voice heard. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Putting the blame on your vendors for the win. </title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/01/22/putting-the-blame-on-your-vendors-for-the-win.html"/>
   <updated>2008-01-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/01/22/putting-the-blame-on-your-vendors-for-the-win</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In the past week there were a couple of companies(&lt;a href=&quot;http://tumblr.com&quot;&gt;tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://37signals.com&quot;&gt;37signals&lt;/a&gt;) who publically blamed Rackspace for the downtime of their sites (tumblr &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.davidville.com/2008/01/21/downtime-today/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and 37signals &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.37signals.com/svn/posts/800-what-happened-this-morning&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.techcrunch.com/2008/01/18/37signals-down-looks-like-rackspace-is-to-blame-again/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) . In both cases the downtime wasn't widespread and was limited to the individual sites. In both cases someone from the respective site blogged about how it was rackspaces fault they were down. It got me thinking...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don't like how these companies are blaming their vendors when their sites are down. I understand how frustrating it is. I totally realize how you want a scape goat. And i have personally had experiences where Rackspace has screwed up and i have said to Jake: &quot;&lt;i&gt;WTF. Rackspace broke all of our shit&lt;/i&gt;&quot; (which was quickly followed up with &quot;&lt;i&gt;Yeah! Rackspace fixed all of our shit&lt;/i&gt;!&quot; - seriously, i love those guys). But what gets me is when that scapegoating and blaming bleeds into the conversation a company has with its clients/consumers. The customers don't need to hear which vendor broke everything, they just want to hear about solutions and uptime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that these companies are basically saying &quot;&lt;i&gt;this is the entity who is at fault. It isn't us. In fact - we are so smart that we don't need them. we are changing hosting.&lt;/i&gt;&quot; But they should be saying “&lt;i&gt;We were down. bummer. we are up now.&lt;/i&gt;” The snideness is quite annoying to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do yall think - should companies be blaming their vendors - or just take the blame on themselves? I think its hard. I know i have blamed people for faults that really lie with myself. It is certainly easier to write off a simple failure that happens to occur on the vendors property as not my fault. But in the end, didn't i pick the vendor? Didn't i make the decisions that put my company in a place where the vendor could fail?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What i would like to see, is companies taking the blame and just rocking through the casual failures. Making sure their clients know that even though there was a failure, that they are on it. That they have their hands in every single part of their infrastructure. One side effect of this blaming is that you ruin the black box effect your customers have with your software. You suddenly have many more complicated pieces of the puzzle and your customers may be leery to trust their data in such a hodgepodge of systems/vendors/etc.  Of course i am hypothesizing here, but i do know that the first time i thought about how tumblr did their infrastructure was not when it went down, but when they blamed rackspace. Before they mentioned that, i just wanted them to be back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am interested to hear what others think of this trend. I am guessing that people will learn that blaming is annoying. I hope that i don't ever do it. I will surely think about this next time i am faced with downtime and have a choice in what to tell my customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;UPDATE: &lt;/b&gt;After talking to &lt;a href=&quot;http://gburt.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Gabriel&lt;/a&gt; last night about this issue - he reminded me of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://joelonsoftware.com/items/2008/01/22.html&quot;&gt;Joel on software post&lt;/a&gt; that influenced me to write this post. His post outlines how I feel a software service company should treat outages and how they should handle them. Specifically how following the five whys philosophy usually ferrets out the root of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Monsters for you to buy and make your friend!</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/01/11/monsters-for-you-to-buy-and-make-your-friend.html"/>
   <updated>2008-01-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/01/11/monsters-for-you-to-buy-and-make-your-friend</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/natatwo/2138986573/&quot; title=&quot;Me and the bunny by nata2, on Flickr&quot;&gt;&lt;img align=&quot;right&quot; src=&quot;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2030/2138986573_9e5a217b62_m.jpg&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;180&quot; alt=&quot;Me and the bunny&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;My brother has been making these awesome little monsters out of socks for a little while. They are pretty cool and quite cute. I recently noticed that his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.etsy.com/shop.php?user_id=5066104&quot;&gt;etsy site&lt;/a&gt; was somehow a bit incomplete - so i thought about what made some of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://shawnimals.com/&quot;&gt;other creature makers&lt;/a&gt; creatures successful. I decided that key was the stories the awesome story about each character and monster really added a lot of personalization to the various creatures. Like shawnimal and his &lt;a href=&quot;http://ninjatown.com/&quot;&gt;ninjatown&lt;/a&gt; people. totally compelling story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So i suggested this to dylan and BAM. he made a whole universe. Pretty awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dylanreed.org/2008/01/10/my-etsy-shoppe-and-the-stories-i-tell/&quot;&gt;Check out his post about it&lt;/a&gt;. But more importantly, &lt;a href=&quot;http://awesomeguy.etsy.com/&quot;&gt;buy some of the little friends he made&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Data Portability feeds</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/01/10/data-portability-feeds.html"/>
   <updated>2008-01-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/01/10/data-portability-feeds</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The future is obviously data and sharing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://dataportability.org/&quot;&gt;dataportability.org&lt;/a&gt; data portability group is pretty awesome. It has a boatload of pretty cool people who are talking about amazing stuff. I have done what i always do whenever i find a movement that i appreciate  and subscribed to all of the participants blogs.  Good stuff thus far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in reading an aggregate - check out my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/reader/shared/user/18273797402131469936/label/DataPortability&quot;&gt;shared DataPortability tag&lt;/a&gt; or subscribe to its &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/reader/public/atom/user/18273797402131469936/label/DataPortability&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;. If you want, I have uploaded an &lt;a href=&quot;http://dopeman.org/dataportability.opml&quot;&gt;OPML of the participants blogs&lt;/a&gt;.  Please &lt;a href=&quot;http://harperreed.org/contact/&quot;&gt;let me know&lt;/a&gt; if i have missed anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can't wait to see what comes out of this group. I hope that i will be able to contribute and use their creation in Threadless and various other application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Obama is winning Iowa!</title>
   <link href="http://localhost:4000/2008/01/03/obama-is-winning-iowa.html"/>
   <updated>2008-01-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://localhost:4000/2008/01/03/obama-is-winning-iowa</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is exciting. Obama is the first candidate I have ever donated money too. Hopefully this will enable his campaign to get enough traction to win on a national level. Hopefully it is Obama and Huckabee against each other. Because then we either get Obama - who is pretty awesome, or Huckabee who is an insane person. INSANE. So either the U.S. will be in a place to repair, or a place to engage in a Holy war with the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway. We just got back from japan. It was amazing. Everyone had a great time. Pictures are up on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/natatwo/sets/72157603616549745/&quot;&gt;flickr&lt;/a&gt;. I will blog about it later.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>



 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
